<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dcat%3Aquant-ph%20AND%20submittedDate%3A%5B202312190000%20TO%20202312192359%5D%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D40" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=cat:quant-ph AND submittedDate:[202312190000 TO 202312192359]&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=40</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/UMtXsyvZWaWrQ7Ugb3nFYzOwphI</id>
  <updated>2024-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">41</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">40</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12643v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T22:39:07Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T22:39:07Z</published>
    <title>Quantifying the magnetic noise power spectrum for ensembles of P1 and NV
  centers in diamond</title>
    <summary>  We use Carr-Purcell-Meiboom-Gill (CPMG) dynamical decoupling to measure the
magnetic noise power spectra for ensembles of P1 and NV centers in diamond
using pulsed electron paramagnetic resonance (pEPR) at 2.5 GHz. The
stroboscopically detected pEPR experiments on NV centers were performed on an
HPHT (high pressure, high temperature) diamond sample at 13 mT and 190 mT,
while the experiments on P1 centers were performed on a CVD (chemical vapor
deposition) diamond sample at 89 mT. All power spectra show two distinct
features, a broad component that is observed to scale as approximately
$1/\omega$, and a prominent peak at the $^{13}$C Larmor precession frequency.
The broad $1/\omega$ behavior is consistent with an inhomogeneous distribution
of Lorentzian spectra due to clustering of P1 centers, which has recently been
shown to be prevalent in HPHT diamond. However, it is unknown if such
clustering occurs in CVD diamond. The maximum rate at which we can apply $\pi$
pulses is higher than the $^{13}$C frequency at 13 mT, but is lower than the
$^{13}$C frequency at 89 mT and 190 mT. We develop techniques that utilize the
higher harmonics of the CPMG filter function to improve our estimate of the
$^{13}$C contribution to the power spectrum at the higher fields. Surprisingly,
the $^{13}$C peak, when measured with higher harmonics of the CPMG filter,
appears larger than expected based on measurements with the lower harmonics. We
assess the robustness of our methods in the presence of finite pulse widths and
flip angle errors. These techniques could be used in a variety of ac
magnetometry and noise spectroscopy measurements such as chemical sensing and
nanoscale nuclear magnetic resonance.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ethan Q. Williams</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chandrasekhar Ramanathan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">30 pages, 20 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12643v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12643v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12614v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T21:38:10Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T21:38:10Z</published>
    <title>Making Existing Quantum Position Verification Protocols Secure Against
  Arbitrary Transmission Loss</title>
    <summary>  Signal loss poses a significant threat to the security of quantum
cryptography when the chosen protocol lacks loss-tolerance. In quantum position
verification (QPV) protocols, even relatively small loss rates can compromise
security. The goal is thus to find protocols that remain secure under
practically achievable loss rates. In this work, we modify the usual structure
of QPV protocols and prove that this modification makes the potentially high
transmission loss between the verifiers and the prover security-irrelevant for
a class of protocols that includes a practically-interesting candidate protocol
inspired by the BB84 protocol ($\mathrm{QPV}_{\mathrm{BB84}}^{f}$). This
modification, which involves photon presence detection, a small time delay at
the prover, and a commitment to play before proceeding, reduces the overall
loss rate to just the prover's laboratory. The adapted protocol
c-$\mathrm{QPV}_{\mathrm{BB84}}^{f}$ then becomes a practically feasible QPV
protocol with strong security guarantees, even against attackers using adaptive
strategies. As the loss rate between the verifiers and prover is mainly
dictated by the distance between them, secure QPV over longer distances becomes
possible. We also show possible implementations of the required photon presence
detection, making c-$\mathrm{QPV}_{\mathrm{BB84}}^{f}$ a protocol that solves
all major practical issues in QPV. Finally, we discuss experimental aspects and
give parameter estimations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Rene Allerstorfer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andreas Bluhm</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Harry Buhrman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthias Christandl</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Llorenç Escolà-Farràs</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Florian Speelman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Philip Verduyn Lunel</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12614v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12614v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12613v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T21:36:07Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T21:36:07Z</published>
    <title>Toward coherent quantum computation of scattering amplitudes with a
  measurement-based photonic quantum processor</title>
    <summary>  In recent years, applications of quantum simulation have been developed to
study properties of strongly interacting theories. This has been driven by two
factors: on the one hand, needs from theorists to have access to physical
observables that are prohibitively difficult to study using classical
computing; on the other hand, quantum hardware becoming increasingly reliable
and scalable to larger systems. In this work, we discuss the feasibility of
using quantum optical simulation for studying scattering observables that are
presently inaccessible via lattice QCD and are at the core of the experimental
program at Jefferson Lab, the future Electron-Ion Collider, and other
accelerator facilities. We show that recent progress in measurement-based
photonic quantum computing can be leveraged to provide deterministic generation
of required exotic gates and implementation in a single photonic quantum
processor.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Raúl A. Briceño</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Robert G. Edwards</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Miller Eaton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Carlos González-Arciniegas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Olivier Pfister</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>George Siopsis</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">26 pages, 7 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12613v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12613v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-lat" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12609v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T21:29:45Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T21:29:45Z</published>
    <title>Three-photon electron spin resonances</title>
    <summary>  We report the observation of a three-photon resonant transition of
charge-carrier spins in an organic light-emitting diode using electrically
detected magnetic resonance (EDMR) spectroscopy at room temperature. Under
strong magnetic-resonant drive (drive field $B_1$ ~ static magnetic field
$B_0$), a $B_0$-field swept EDMR line emerges when $B_0$ is approximately
threefold the one-photon resonance field. Ratios of drive-induced shifts of
this line to those of two- and one-photon shifts agree with analytical
expressions derived from the Floquet Hamiltonian and confirm the nature of
these three-photon transitions, enabling access of spin physics to a hitherto
inaccessible domain of quantum mechanics.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>S. I. Atwood</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, USA</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>V. V. Mkhitaryan</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Institut für Experimentelle und Angewandte Physik, Universität Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Dhileepkumar</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, USA</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Nuibe</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, USA</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Hosseinzadeh</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, USA</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>H. Malissa</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, USA</arxiv:affiliation>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Institut für Experimentelle und Angewandte Physik, Universität Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. M. Lupton</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, USA</arxiv:affiliation>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Institut für Experimentelle und Angewandte Physik, Universität Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>C. Boehme</name>
      <arxiv:affiliation xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, USA</arxiv:affiliation>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">32 pages, 18 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12609v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12609v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12593v2</id>
    <updated>2023-12-29T14:33:59Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T20:41:14Z</published>
    <title>Spread complexity in saddle-dominated scrambling</title>
    <summary>  Recently, the concept of spread complexity, Krylov complexity for states, has
been introduced as a measure of the complexity and chaoticity of quantum
systems. In this paper, we study the spread complexity of the thermofield
double state within \emph{integrable} systems that exhibit saddle-dominated
scrambling. Specifically, we focus on the Lipkin-Meshkov-Glick model and the
inverted harmonic oscillator as representative examples of quantum mechanical
systems featuring saddle-dominated scrambling. Applying the Lanczos algorithm,
our numerical investigation reveals that the spread complexity in these systems
exhibits features reminiscent of \emph{chaotic} systems, displaying a
distinctive ramp-peak-slope-plateau pattern. Our results indicate that,
although spread complexity serves as a valuable probe, accurately diagnosing
true quantum chaos generally necessitates additional physical input. We also
explore the relationship between spread complexity, the spectral form factor,
and the transition probability within the Krylov space. We provide analytical
confirmation of our numerical results, validating the Ehrenfest theorem of
complexity and identifying a distinct quadratic behavior in the early-time
regime of spread complexity.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kyoung-Bum Huh</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hyun-Sik Jeong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Juan F. Pedraza</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">v1: 27 pages, 17 figures; v2: references added</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12593v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12593v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="nlin.CD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13300v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T20:29:45Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T20:29:45Z</published>
    <title>Contextual Measurement Model and Quantum Theory</title>
    <summary>  We develop the contextual measurement model (CMM) which is used for
clarification of the quantum foundations. This model matches with Bohr's views
on the role of experimental contexts. CMM is based on contextual probability
theory which is connected with generalized probability theory. CMM covers
measurements in classical, quantum, and semi-classical physics. The CMM
formalism is illustrated by a few examples. We consider CMM framing of
classical probability, the von Neumann measurement theory, the quantum
instrument theory. CMM can also be applied outside of physics, in cognition,
decision making, and psychology, so called quantum-like modeling.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrei Khrennikov</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13300v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13300v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.PR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12537v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T19:14:08Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T19:14:08Z</published>
    <title>Quantum steering ellipsoids and quantum obesity in critical systems</title>
    <summary>  Quantum obesity (QO) is new function used to quantify quantum correlations
beyond entanglement, which also works as a witness for entanglement. Thanks to
its analyticity for arbitrary state of bipartite systems, it represents an
advantage with respect to other quantum correlations, like quantum discord for
example. In this work we show that QO is a fundamental quantity to observe
signature of quantum phase transitions. We also describe a mechanism based on
local filtering operations able to intensify the critical behavior of the QO
near to the transition point. To this end, we introduce a theorem stating how
QO changes under local quantum operations and classical communications. This
work opens perspective for the characterization of new phenomena in quantum
critical systems through the analytically computable pairwise QO.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Pedro Rosario</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alan C. Santos</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">8 pages and 3 figures. Comments are welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12537v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12537v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12513v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T19:00:04Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T19:00:04Z</published>
    <title>Entropy production in the mesoscopic-leads formulation of quantum
  thermodynamics</title>
    <summary>  Understanding the entropy production of systems strongly coupled to thermal
baths is a core problem of both quantum thermodynamics and mesoscopic physics.
While there exist many techniques to accurately study entropy production in
such systems, they typically require a microscopic description of the baths,
which can become numerically intractable to study for large systems.
Alternatively an open-systems approach can be employed with all the nuances
associated with various levels of approximation. Recently, the mesoscopic leads
approach has emerged as a powerful method for studying such quantum systems
strongly coupled to multiple thermal baths. In this method, a set of
discretised lead modes, each locally damped, provide a Markovian embedding.
Here we show that this method proves extremely useful to describe entropy
production of a strongly coupled open quantum system. We show numerically, for
both non-interacting and interacting setups, that a system coupled to a single
bath exhibits a thermal fixed point at the level of the embedding. This allows
us to use various results from the thermodynamics of quantum dynamical
semi-groups to infer the non-equilibrium thermodynamics of the strongly
coupled, non-Markovian central systems. In particular, we show that the entropy
production in the transient regime recovers the well established microscopic
definitions of entropy production with a correction that can be computed
explicitly for both the single- and multiple-lead cases.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Artur Lacerda</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael J. Kewming</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marlon Brenes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Conor Jackson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen R. Clark</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mark T. Mitchison</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>John Goold</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">v1: 11 pages, 6 figures, comments welcome as always!</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12513v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12513v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12506v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T19:00:02Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T19:00:02Z</published>
    <title>Hamiltonian truncation tensor networks for quantum field theories</title>
    <summary>  Understanding the equilibrium properties and out of equilibrium dynamics of
quantum field theories are key aspects of fundamental problems in theoretical
particle physics and cosmology. However, their classical simulation is highly
challenging. In this work, we introduce a tensor network method for the
classical simulation of continuous quantum field theories that is suitable for
the study of low-energy eigenstates and out-of-equilibrium time evolution. The
method is built on Hamiltonian truncation and tensor network techniques,
bridging the gap between two successful approaches. One of the key developments
is the exact construction of matrix product state representations of global
projectors, crucial for the implementation of interacting theories. Despite
featuring a relatively high computational effort, our method dramatically
improves predictive precision compared to exact diagonalisation-based
Hamiltonian truncation, allowing the study of so far unexplored parameter
regimes and dynamical effects. We corroborate trust in the accuracy of the
method by comparing it with exact theoretical results for ground state
properties of the sine-Gordon model. We then proceed with discussing
$(1+1)$-dimensional quantum electrodynamics, the massive Schwinger model, for
which we accurately locate its critical point and study the growth and
saturation of momentum-space entanglement in sudden quenches.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Philipp Schmoll</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jan Naumann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Nietner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jens Eisert</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Spyros Sotiriadis</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">26 pages, 14 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12506v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12506v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12509v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T19:00:02Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T19:00:02Z</published>
    <title>The entanglement membrane in exactly solvable lattice models</title>
    <summary>  Entanglement membrane theory is an effective coarse-grained description of
entanglement dynamics and operator growth in chaotic quantum many-body systems.
The fundamental quantity characterizing the membrane is the entanglement line
tension. However, determining the entanglement line tension for microscopic
models is in general exponentially difficult. We compute the entanglement line
tension in a recently introduced class of exactly solvable yet chaotic unitary
circuits, so-called generalized dual-unitary circuits, obtaining a non-trivial
form that gives rise to a hierarchy of velocity scales with $v_E&lt;v_B$. We find
that these circuits saturate certain bounds on entanglement growth that are
also saturated in holographic models. Furthermore, we relate the entanglement
line tension to temporal entanglement and correlation functions. We also find
new methods of constructing generalized dual-unitary gates beyond qubits that
display behavior unique to local dimension $\geq3$. Our results shed light on
entanglement membrane theory in microscopic Floquet lattice models and enable
us to perform non-trivial checks on the validity of its predictions by
comparison to exact and numerical calculations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michael A. Rampp</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Suhail A. Rather</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pieter W. Claeys</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages, 6 figures + 3 pages of appendices</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12509v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12509v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="nlin.CD" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12427v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T18:56:03Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T18:56:03Z</published>
    <title>Enhancing quantum utility: simulating large-scale quantum spin chains on
  superconducting quantum computers</title>
    <summary>  We present the quantum simulation of the frustrated quantum
spin-$\frac{1}{2}$ antiferromagnetic Heisenberg spin chain with competing
nearest-neighbor $(J_1)$ and next-nearest-neighbor $(J_2)$ exchange
interactions in the real superconducting quantum computer with qubits ranging
up to 100. In particular, we implement, for the first time, the Hamiltonian
with the next-nearest neighbor exchange interaction in conjunction with the
nearest neighbor interaction on IBM's superconducting quantum computer and
carry out the time evolution of the spin chain by employing first-order
Trotterization. Furthermore, our novel implementation of second-order
Trotterization for the isotropic Heisenberg spin chain, involving only
nearest-neighbor exchange interaction, enables precise measurement of the
expectation values of staggered magnetization observable across a range of up
to 100 qubits. Notably, in both cases, our approach results in a constant
circuit depth in each Trotter step, independent of the initial number of
qubits. Our demonstration of the accurate measurement of expectation values for
the large-scale quantum system using superconducting quantum computers
designates the quantum utility of these devices for investigating various
properties of many-body quantum systems. This will be a stepping stone to
achieving the quantum advantage over classical ones in simulating quantum
systems before the fault tolerance quantum era.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Talal Ahmed Chowdhury</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kwangmin Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mahmud Ashraf Shamim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. L. Kabir</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Sabbir Sufian</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">23 pages + references, 11 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12427v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12427v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-lat" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12386v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T18:18:51Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T18:18:51Z</published>
    <title>Quantum Equation of Motion with Orbital Optimization for Computing
  Molecular Properties in Near-Term Quantum Computing</title>
    <summary>  Determining the properties of molecules and materials is one of the premier
applications of quantum computing. A major question in the field is how to use
imperfect near-term quantum computers to solve problems of practical value.
Inspired by the recently developed variants of the quantum counterpart of the
equation-of-motion (qEOM) approach and the orbital-optimized variational
quantum eigensolver (oo-VQE), we present a quantum algorithm (oo-VQE-qEOM) for
the calculation of molecular properties by computing expectation values on a
quantum computer. We perform noise-free quantum simulations of BeH$_2$ in the
series of STO-3G/6-31G/6-31G* basis sets, H$_4$ and H$_2$O in 6-31G using an
active space of four electrons and four spatial orbitals (8 qubits) to evaluate
excitation energies, electronic absorption, and for twisted H$_4$, circular
dichroism spectra. We demonstrate that the proposed algorithm can reproduce the
results of conventional classical CASSCF calculations for these molecular
systems.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Phillip W. K. Jensen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Erik Rosendahl Kjellgren</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peter Reinholdt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Karl Michael Ziems</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sonia Coriani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kongsted</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stephan P. A. Sauer</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">17+12 pages, 3 figures, 1 table; comments welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12386v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12386v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12372v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T18:04:22Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T18:04:22Z</published>
    <title>Frequency-resolved Purcell effect for the dissipative generation of
  steady-state entanglement</title>
    <summary>  We report a driven-dissipative mechanism to generate stationary entangled $W$
states among strongly-interacting quantum emitters placed within a cavity.
Driving the ensemble into the highest energy state -- whether coherently or
incoherently -- enables a subsequent cavity-enhanced decay into an entangled
steady state consisting of a single de-excitation shared coherently among all
emitters, i.e., a $W$ state, well known for its robustness against qubit loss.
The non-harmonic energy structure of the interacting ensemble allows this
transition to be resonantly selected by the cavity, while quenching subsequent
off-resonant decays. Evidence of this purely dissipative mechanism should be
observable in state-of-the-art cavity QED systems in the solid-state, enabling
new prospects for the scalable stabilization of quantum states in dissipative
quantum platforms.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alejandro Vivas-Viaña</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Diego Martín-Cano</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Carlos Sánchez Muñoz</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">5 pages, 3 figures, Supplemental Material with 8 pages, 5 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12372v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12372v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.atom-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12350v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T17:28:54Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T17:28:54Z</published>
    <title>Work and efficiency fluctuations in a quantum Otto cycle with idle
  levels</title>
    <summary>  We study the performance of a quantum Otto heat engine with two spins coupled
by a Heisenberg interaction, taking into account not only the mean values of
work and efficiency but also their fluctuations. We first show that, for this
system, the output work and its fluctuations are directly related to the
magnetization and magnetic susceptibility of the system at equilibrium with
either heat bath. We analyze the regions where the work extraction can be done
with low relative fluctuation for a given range of temperatures, while still
achieving an efficiency higher than that of a single spin system heat engine.
In particular, we find that, due to the presence of `idle' levels, an increase
in the inter-spin coupling can either increase or decrease fluctuations,
depending on the other parameters. In all cases, however, we find that the
relative fluctuations in work or efficiency remain large, implying that this
microscopic engine is not very reliable as a source of work.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Maron F. Anka</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thiago R. de Oliveira</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Jonathan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">13 pages, 11 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12350v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12350v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12336v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T17:03:35Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T17:03:35Z</published>
    <title>Optical Feedback Loop in Paraxial Fluids of Light: A Gate to new
  phenomena in analogue physical simulations</title>
    <summary>  Easily accessible through tabletop experiments based on laser propagation
inside nonlinear optical media, Paraxial Fluids of Light are emerging as
promising platforms for the simulation and exploration of quantum-like
phenomena. In particular, the analogy builds on a formal equivalence between
the governing model for a Bose-Einstein Condensate under the mean-field
approximation and the model of laser propagation under the paraxial
approximation. Yet, the fact that the role of time is played by the propagation
distance in the optical analogue system may impose strong bounds on the range
of accessible phenomena due to the limited length of the nonlinear medium. In
this manuscript, we present a novel experimental approach to solve this
limitation in the form of an optical feedback loop, which consists of the
reconstruction of the optical states at the end of the system followed by their
subsequent re-injection exploiting wavefront shaping techniques. The results
enclosed demonstrate the potential of this approach to access unprecedented
dynamics, paving for the observation of novel phenomena in these systems.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tiago D. Ferreira</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ariel Guerreiro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nuno A. Silva</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12336v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12336v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.optics" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.optics" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12320v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T16:44:49Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T16:44:49Z</published>
    <title>Accurate harmonic vibrational frequencies for diatomic molecules via
  quantum computing</title>
    <summary>  During the noisy intermediate-scale quantum (NISQ) era, quantum computational
approaches refined to overcome the challenge of limited quantum resources are
highly valuable. However, the accuracy of the molecular properties predicted by
most of the quantum computations nowadays is still far off (not within chemical
accuracy) compared to their corresponding experimental data. Here, we propose a
promising qubit-efficient quantum computational approach to calculate the
harmonic vibrational frequencies of a large set of neutral closed-shell
diatomic molecules with results in great agreement with their experimental
data. To this end, we construct the accurate Hamiltonian using molecular
orbitals, derived from density functional theory to account for the electron
correlation and expanded in the Daubechies wavelet basis set to allow an
accurate representation in real space grid points, where an optimized compact
active space is further selected so that only a reduced small number of qubits
is sufficient to yield an accurate result. To justify the approach, we
benchmark the performance of the Hamiltonians spanned by the selected molecular
orbitals by first transforming the molecular Hamiltonians into qubit
Hamiltonians and then using the exact diagonalization method to calculate the
results, regarded as the best results achievable by quantum computation.
Furthermore, we show that the variational quantum circuit with the
chemistry-inspired UCCSD ansatz can achieve the same accuracy as the exact
diagonalization method except for systems whose Mayer bond order indices are
larger than 2. For those systems, we demonstrate that the heuristic
hardware-efficient RealAmplitudes ansatz, even with a shorter circuit depth,
can provide a significant improvement over the UCCSD ansatz, verifying that the
harmonic vibrational frequencies could be calculated accurately by quantum
computation in the NISQ era.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Shih-Kai Chou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jyh-Pin Chou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Hu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuan-Chung Cheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hsi-Sheng Goan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043216</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043216" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">17 pages, 5 figures plus 11-page supplemental material</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Physical Review Research 5, 043216 (2023)</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12320v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12320v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12310v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T16:30:44Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T16:30:44Z</published>
    <title>Quantum squeezing induced quantum entanglement and EPR steering in
  coupled optomechanical system</title>
    <summary>  We propose a theoretical project in which quantum squeezing induces quantum
entanglement and Einstein-Podolsky-Rosen steering in a coupled
whispering-gallery-mode optomechanical system. Through pumping the
$\chi^{(2)}$-nonlinear resonator with the phase matching condition, the
generated squeezed resonator mode and the mechanical mode of the optomechanical
resonator can generate strong quantum entanglement and EPR steering, where the
squeezing of the nonlinear resonator plays the vital role. The transitions from
zero entanglement to strong entanglement and one-way steering to two-way
steering can be realized by adjusting the system parameters appropriately. The
photon-photon entanglement and steering between the two resonators can also be
obtained by deducing the amplitude of the driving laser. Our project does not
need an extraordinarily squeezed field, and it is convenient to manipulate and
provides a novel and flexible avenue for diverse applications in quantum
technology dependent on both optomechanical and photon-photon entanglement and
steering.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Shao-Xiong Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cheng-Hua Bai</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gang Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chang-shui Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tiancai Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1364/OE.510160</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1364/OE.510160" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Opt. Express, 32, 260-274 (2024)</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12310v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12310v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12291v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T16:14:01Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T16:14:01Z</published>
    <title>Quench dynamics in higher-dimensional Holstein models: Insights from
  Truncated Wigner Approaches</title>
    <summary>  Charge-density wave phases in quantum materials stem from the complex
interplay of electronic and lattice degrees of freedom. Nowadays, various
time-resolved spectroscopy techniques allow to actively manipulate such phases
and monitor their dynamics in real time. Modeling such nonequilibrium dynamics
theoretically is a great challenge and exact methods can usually only treat a
small number of atoms and finitely many phonons. We approach the melting of
charge-density waves in a Holstein model after a sudden switch-on of the
electronic hopping from two perspectives: We prove that in the non-interacting
and in the strong-coupling limit, the CDW order parameter on high-dimensional
hypercubic lattices obeys a factorization relation for long times, such that
its dynamics can be reduced to the one-dimensional case. Secondly, we present
numerical results from semiclassical techniques based on the Truncated Wigner
Approximation for two spatial dimensions. A comparison with exact data obtained
for a Holstein chain shows that a semiclassical treatment of both the electrons
and phonons is required in order to correctly describe the phononic dynamics.
This is confirmed, in addition, for a quench in the electron-phonon coupling
strength.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Eva Paprotzki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alexander Osterkorn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Vibhu Mishra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stefan Kehrein</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Figure data is attached</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12291v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12291v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12256v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T15:39:37Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T15:39:37Z</published>
    <title>Cavity-resonated detection of spin polarization in a microfabricated
  atomic vapor cell</title>
    <summary>  We demonstrate continuous Pound-Drever-Hall (PDH) nondestructive monitoring
of the electron spin polarization of an atomic vapor in a microfabricated vapor
cell within an optical resonator. The two-chamber silicon and glass cell
contains $^{87}$Rb and 1.3 amagat of N$_{2}$ buffer gas, and is placed within a
planar optical resonator formed by two mirrors with dichroic dielectric
coatings to resonantly enhance the coupling to phase-modulated probe light near
the D$_2$ line at 780 nm. We describe the theory of signal generation in this
system, including the spin-dependent complex refractive index, cavity optical
transfer functions, and PDH signal response to spin polarization. We observe
cavity transmission and PDH signals across $\approx 200$ GHz of detuning around
the atomic resonance line. By resonant optical pumping on the 795 nm D$_1$
line, we observe spin-dependent cavity line shifts, in good agreement with
theory. We use the saturation of the line shift vs. optical pumping power to
calibrate the number density and efficiency of the optical pumping. In the
unresolved sideband regime, we observe quantum-noise-limited PDH readout of the
spin polarization density, with a flat noise floor of $9 \times 10^9$ spins
cm$^{-3}$ Hz$^{-1/2}$ for frequencies above 700 Hz. We note possible extensions
of the technique.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>María Hernández Ruiz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yintao Ma</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hana Medhat</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Vito Giovanni Lucivero</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Morgan W. Mitchell</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12256v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12256v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.atom-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.atom-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12239v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T15:23:55Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T15:23:55Z</published>
    <title>Solvable entanglement dynamics in quantum circuits with generalized dual
  unitarity</title>
    <summary>  We study the non-equilibrium dynamics of kicked Ising models in $1+1$
dimensions which have interactions alternating between odd and even bonds in
time. These models give rise to time-evolution equivalent to quantum circuits
having both the global property of tri-unitarity (three 'arrows of time') and
also the local property of second-level dual-unitarity, which constrains the
behavior of pairs of local gates underlying the circuit under a space-time
rotation. We identify a broad class of initial product states wherein the
effect of the environment on a small subsystem can be exactly represented by
influence matrices with simple Markovian structures, resulting in the
subsystem's full dynamics being efficiently computable. We further find
additional conditions under which the dynamics of entanglement can be solved
for all times, yielding rich phenomenology ranging from linear growth at half
the maximal speed allowed by locality, followed by saturation to maximum
entropy (i.e., thermalization to infinite temperature); to entanglement growth
with saturation to extensive but sub-maximal entropy. Our findings extend our
knowledge of interacting quantum systems whose thermalizing dynamics can be
efficiently and analytically computed, going beyond the well-known examples of
integrable models, Clifford circuits, and dual-unitary circuits.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chuan Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wen Wei Ho</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">6 + 22 pages, 3 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12239v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12239v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12212v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T14:57:46Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T14:57:46Z</published>
    <title>Transient Temperature Dynamics of Reservoirs Connected Through an Open
  Quantum System</title>
    <summary>  The dynamics of open quantum systems connected with several reservoirs
attract great attention due to its importance in quantum optics, biology,
quantum thermodynamics, transport phenomena, etc. In many problems, the Born
approximation is applicable which implies that the influence of the open
quantum system on the reservoirs can be neglected. However, in the case of a
long-time dynamics or mesoscopic reservoir, the reverse influence can be
crucial. In this paper, we investigate the transient dynamics of several
bosonic reservoirs connected through an open quantum system. We use an
adiabatic approach to study the temporal dynamics of temperatures of the
reservoirs during relaxation to thermodynamic equilibrium. We show that there
are various types of temperature dynamics that strongly depend on the values of
dissipative rates and initial temperatures. We demonstrate that temperatures of
the reservoirs can exhibit non-monotonic behavior. Moreover, there are moments
of time during which the reservoir with initially intermediate temperature
becomes the hottest or coldest reservoir. The obtained results pave the way for
managing energy flows in mesoscale and nanoscale systems.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>I. V. Vovchenko</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. A. Zyablovsky</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. A. Pukhov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. S. Andrianov</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12212v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12212v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12172v2</id>
    <updated>2023-12-21T18:28:01Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T14:03:40Z</published>
    <title>Reassessing the advantage of indefinite causal orders for quantum
  metrology</title>
    <summary>  The quantum switch, the canonical example of a process with indefinite causal
order, has been claimed to provide various advantages over processes with
definite causal orders for some particular tasks in the field of quantum
metrology. In this work, we argue that some of these advantages in fact do not
hold if a fairer comparison is made. To this end, we consider a framework that
allows for a proper comparison between the performance, quantified by the
quantum Fisher information, of different classes of indefinite causal order
processes and that of causal strategies on a given metrological task. More
generally, by considering the recently proposed classes of circuits with
classical or quantum control of the causal order, we come up with different
examples where processes with indefinite causal order offer (or not) an
advantage over processes with definite causal order, qualifying the interest of
indefinite causal order regarding quantum metrology. As it turns out, for a
range of examples, the class of quantum circuits with quantum control of causal
order, which are known to be physically realizable, is shown to provide a
strict advantage over causally ordered quantum circuits as well as over the
class of quantum circuits with causal superposition. Thus, considering this
class provides new evidence that indefinite causal order strategies can
strictly outperform definite causal order strategies in quantum metrology.
Moreover, it shows that the so-called dynamical control of causal order, a
feature of quantum circuits with quantum control of the causal order but not of
quantum circuits with mere causal superposition, can be a useful resource in
quantum metrology.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Raphaël Mothe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cyril Branciard</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alastair A. Abbott</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12172v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12172v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12168v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T14:02:16Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T14:02:16Z</published>
    <title>Phase Retrieval in Incoherent Diffractive Imaging using higher-order
  photon correlation functions</title>
    <summary>  To obtain spatial information about an arbitrary object in x-ray structure
analysis, the standard method is to measure the intensity in the far field,
i.e., the first-order photon correlation function of the coherently scattered
x-ray photons (coherent diffractive imaging). Recently, it was suggested to
record alternatively the incoherently scattered photons and measure the
second-order photon correlation function to reconstruct the geometry of the
unknown object (incoherent diffractive imaging). Yet, besides various
advantages of the latter method, both techniques suffer from the so-called
phase retrieval problem. Lately, an ab-initio phase retrieval algorithm to
reconstruct the phase of the so-called structure factor of the scattering
objects based on the third-order photon correlation function was reported. The
algorithm makes use of the so-called closure phase, which contains important,
yet incomplete phase information, well-known from triple correlations and their
bispectrum in speckle masking and astronomy applications. Here, we provide a
detailed analysis of the underlying scheme and quantities in the context of
x-ray structure analysis. In particular, we explicitly calculate the
third-order photon correlation function in a full quantum mechanical treatment
and discuss the uniqueness of the closure phase equations constructed from it.
In this context, we recapitulate the sign problem of the closure phase and how
it can be lifted using redundant information. We further show how the algorithm
can be improved using even higher-order photon correlation functions, e.g., the
fourth-order correlation function, delivering new phase relations appearing in
the four-point correlations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>M. Bojer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Eckert</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Karl</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>S. Richter</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. von Zanthier</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12168v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12168v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12161v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T13:48:58Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T13:48:58Z</published>
    <title>Towards an in-depth detection of malware using distributed QCNN</title>
    <summary>  Malware detection is an important topic of current cybersecurity, and Machine
Learning appears to be one of the main considered solutions even if certain
problems to generalize to new malware remain. In the aim of exploring the
potential of quantum machine learning on this domain, our previous work showed
that quantum neural networks do not perform well on image-based malware
detection when using a few qubits. In order to enhance the performances of our
quantum algorithms for malware detection using images, without increasing the
resources needed in terms of qubits, we implement a new preprocessing of our
dataset using Grayscale method, and we couple it with a model composed of five
distributed quantum convolutional networks and a scoring function. We get an
increase of around 20 \% of our results, both on the accuracy of the test and
its F1-score.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tony Quertier</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Grégoire Barrué</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12161v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12161v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12118v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T12:48:30Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T12:48:30Z</published>
    <title>Iteration-Dependent Scaled Min-Sum Decoding for Low-Complexity Key
  Reconciliation in CV-QKD</title>
    <summary>  We introduce an iteration-dependent scaled min-sum decoding for low-rate LDPC
codes in CV-QKD, achieving near-sum product algorithm performance with reduced
complexity, and facilitating CV-QKD hardware implementation.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Erdem Eray Cil</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Laurent Schmalen</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted and to be presented at the Optical Fiber Communication
  Conference (OFC) 2024</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12118v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12118v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.IT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12101v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T12:25:22Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T12:25:22Z</published>
    <title>Quantum Tunnelling and Thermally Driven Transitions in a Double Well
  Potential at Finite Temperature</title>
    <summary>  We explore dissipative quantum tunnelling, a phenomenon central to various
physical and chemical processes, using a double-well potential model. This
paper aims to bridge gaps in understanding the crossover from thermal
activation to quantum tunnelling, a domain still shrouded in mystery despite
extensive research. We study a Caldeira-Leggett-derived model of quantum
Brownian motion and investigate the Lindblad and stochastic Schr\"{o}dinger
dynamics numerically, seeking to offer new insights into the transition states
in the crossover region. Our study has implications for quantum computing and
understanding fundamental natural processes, highlighting the significance of
quantum effects on transition rates and temperature influences on tunnelling.
  Additionally, we introduce a new model for quantum Brownian motion which
takes Lindblad form and is formulated as a modification of the widely known
model found in Breuer and Petruccione. In our approach, we remove the
zero-temperature singularity resulting in a better description of
low-temperature quantum Brownian motion near a potential minima.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robson Christie</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jessica Eastman</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">20 pages, 14 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12101v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12101v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.MP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="82B10 (Primary) 81S25 (Secondary)" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12054v2</id>
    <updated>2023-12-25T06:34:10Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T11:17:45Z</published>
    <title>Effects of cavity-mediated processes on the polarization entanglement of
  photon pairs emitted from quantum dots</title>
    <summary>  Semiconductor quantum dots are among the best sources of on-demand entangled
photon pairs. The degree of entanglement, however, is generally limited by the
fine structure splitting of exciton states. In this paper, we theoretically
investigate the generation of polarisation-entangled photon pairs under
two-photon excitation and cavity-assisted two-photon emission, both in the weak
and strong cavity coupling regimes. We demonstrate and clarify that cavity
coupling together with an excitation pulse reduces the degree of entanglement
in three different ways. Firstly, in a strong coupling regime, cavity
introduces the unequal ac-Stark shift of horizontally and vertically polarised
exciton states, which results in the effective splitting of exciton states.
Secondly, it induces the cross-coupling between the exciton states even in the
weak coupling regime, causing the creation of unfavorable two-photon states.
Finally, higher excited states of the cavity modes also contribute to the
reduction of entanglement. Therefore, in the setting considered here, cavity
coupling, which is generally required for the efficient collection of emitted
photons, degrades the entanglement both in weak and strong coupling regimes.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Mukesh Kumar Samal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Divya Mishra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Parvendra Kumar</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages, 9 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12054v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12054v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12048v2</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T12:44:06Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T11:05:38Z</published>
    <title>Irreversible behaviour of a gas owing to Unruh radiation</title>
    <summary>  When gas molecules collide, they accelerate, and therefore encounter the
Fulling-Davies-Unruh and Moore-DeWitt effects. The size of these effects is
sufficient to randomize the motion of the gas molecules after about 1
nanosecond at standard temperature and pressure. Such observations show that
quantum field theory modifies what is required to isolate a physical system
sufficiently for its behaviour to be unitary. In practice the requirements are
never satisfied exactly. Therefore the evolution of the observable universe is
non-unitary and thermodynamically irreversible.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew M. Steane</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">8 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12048v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12048v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12047v2</id>
    <updated>2024-01-09T17:25:00Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T11:01:19Z</published>
    <title>Jordan Algebraic Formulation of Quantum Mechanics and The
  Non-commutative Landau Problem</title>
    <summary>  We present a Jordan algebraic formulation of the non-commutative Landau
problem coupled to a harmonic potential. To achieve this, an alternative
formulation of the Hilbert space version of quantum mechanics is presented.
Using this construction, the Hilbert space corresponding to the non-commutative
Landau problem is obtained. Non-commutative parameters are then described in
terms of an associator in the Jordan algebraic setting. Pure states and density
matrices arising from this problem are characterized. This in turn leads us to
the Jordan-Schr\"odinger time-evolution equation for the state vectors for this
specific problem.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tekin Dereli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ekin Sıla Yörük</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12047v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12047v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.MP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12040v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T10:49:41Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T10:49:41Z</published>
    <title>Transitive Nonlocal Games</title>
    <summary>  We study a class of nonlocal games, called transitive games, for which the
set of perfect strategies forms a semigroup. We establish several interesting
correspondences of bisynchronous transitive games with the theory of compact
quantum groups. In particular, we associate a quantum permutation group with
each bisynchronous transitive game and vice versa. We prove that the existence
of a C*-strategy, the existence of a quantum commuting strategy, and the
existence of a classical strategy are all equivalent for bisynchronous
transitive games. We then use some of these correspondences to establish
necessary and sufficient conditions for some classes of correlations, that
arise as perfect strategies of transitive games, to be nonlocal.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Prem Nigam Kar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jitendra Prakash</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David E Roberson</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12040v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12040v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.QA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12034v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T10:42:04Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T10:42:04Z</published>
    <title>Boosting energy transfer between quantum devices through spectrum
  engineering in the dissipative ultrastrong coupling regime</title>
    <summary>  The coherent energy transfer between two quantum devices (a quantum charger
and a quantum battery) mediated by a photonic cavity is investigated, in
presence of dissipative environments, with particular focus on the the
ultrastrong coupling regime. Here, very short transfer times and high charging
power can be achieved in comparison with the usually addressed weak coupling
case. Such phenomenology is further magnified by the presence of level
crossings appearing in the energy spectrum and which reveal very robust against
dissipative environmental effects. Moreover, by carefully control the physical
parameters of the model, e.g. the matter-radiation coupling and the frequencies
of the system, it is possible to tune these crossings making this device more
flexible and experimentally feasible. Finally to broaden our analysis, we
assume the possibility of choosing between a Fock and a coherent initial state
of the cavity, with the latter showing better energetic performances.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alba Crescente</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dario Ferraro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maura Sassetti</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">13 pages, 11 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12034v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12034v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11946v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T08:43:44Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T08:43:44Z</published>
    <title>Further Exercises about Sporadic SICs</title>
    <summary>  I review some recent technical developments in quantum information theory by
rephrasing them in the form of exercises.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Blake C. Stacey</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">9 pages of homework, just in time for the holidays</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11946v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11946v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11941v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T08:40:23Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T08:40:23Z</published>
    <title>Entanglement transition in deep neural quantum states</title>
    <summary>  Despite the huge theoretical potential of neural quantum states, their use in
describing generic, highly-correlated quantum many-body systems still often
poses practical difficulties. Customized network architectures are under active
investigation to address these issues. For a guided search of suited network
architectures a deepened understanding of the link between neural network
properties and attributes of the physical system one is trying to describe, is
imperative. Drawing inspiration from the field of machine learning, in this
work we show how information propagation in deep neural networks impacts the
physical entanglement properties of deep neural quantum states. In fact, we
link a previously identified information propagation phase transition of a
neural network to a similar transition of entanglement in neural quantum
states. With this bridge we can identify optimal neural quantum state
hyperparameter regimes for representing area as well as volume law entangled
states. The former are easily accessed by alternative methods, such as tensor
network representations, at least in low physical dimensions, while the latter
are challenging to describe generally due to their extensive quantum
entanglement. This advance of our understanding of network configurations for
accurate quantum state representation helps to develop effective
representations to deal with volume-law quantum states, and we apply these
findings to describe the ground state (area law state) vs. the excited state
(volume law state) properties of the prototypical next-nearest neighbor
spin-1/2 Heisenberg model.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Giacomo Passetti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dante M. Kennes</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11941v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11941v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.dis-nn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11924v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T08:04:17Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T08:04:17Z</published>
    <title>Co-propagation of QKD &amp; 6 Tb/s (60x100G) DWDM channels with ~17 dBm
  total WDM power in single and multi-span configurations</title>
    <summary>  We report co-propagation experiments of the quantum channel (at 1310 nm) of a
Quantum Key Distribution (QKD) system with Dense Wavelength Division
Multiplexing (DWDM) data channels in the 1550 nm range. Two configurations are
assessed. The first one is a single span configuration where various lengths of
Standard Single Mode Fiber (SSMF) (from 20 to 70 km) are used and the total WDM
channels power is varied. The Secure Key Rate (SKR) and the Quantum Bit Error
Ratio (QBER) are recorded showing that up to ~17 dBm total power of 30 or 60
channels at 100 Gb/s can coexist with the quantum channel. A metric to evaluate
the co-propagation efficiency is also proposed to better evaluate the ability
of a QKD system to provide secure keys in a co-propagation regime. The second
experiment is a three spans link with a cascade of three QKD systems and two
trusted nodes in a 184 km total link length. We report the transmission of a
coherent 400 Gb/s Dual Polarization DP-16QAM (Quadrature Amplitude Modulation)
channel that transports a QKD secured 100 GbE data stream, with other
fifty-four 100 Gb/s WDM channels. Encryption is demonstrated at the same time
as co-propagation.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>P. Gavignet</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>E. Pincemin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Herviou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Y. Loussouarn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>F. Mondain</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. J. Grant</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>L. Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. I. Woodward</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. F. Dynes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>B. Summers</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. J. Shields</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. Taira</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>H. Sato</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Zink</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>V. Grempka</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>V. Castay</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. Zou</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1109/JLT.2023.3324840</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JLT.2023.3324840" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:2305.13742</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11924v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11924v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11864v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T05:26:03Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T05:26:03Z</published>
    <title>Macroscopic entanglement between ferrimagnetic magnons and atoms via
  crossed optical cavity</title>
    <summary>  We consider a two-dimensional opto-magnomechanical (OMM) system including two
optical cavity modes, a magnon mode, a phonon mode, and a collection of
two-level atoms. In this study, we demonstrate the methodology for generating
stationary entanglement between two-level atoms and magnons, which are
implemented using two optical cavities inside the setup. Additionally, we
investigate the efficiency of transforming entanglement from atom-phonon
entanglement to atom-magnon entanglement. The magnons are stimulated by both a
bias magnetic field and a microwave magnetic field, and they interact with
phonons through the mechanism of magnetostrictive interaction. This interaction
generates magnomechanical displacement, which couples to an optical cavity via
radiation pressure. We demonstrate that by carefully selecting the frequency
detuning of an optical cavity, it is possible to achieve an increase in
bipartite entanglements. Furthermore, this improvement is found to be resistant
to changes in temperature. The entanglement between atoms and magnons plays a
crucial role in the construction of hybrid quantum networks. Our modeling
approach exhibits potential applications in the field of magneto-optical trap
systems as well.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ke Di</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xi Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Huarong Xia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yinxue Zhao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anyu Cheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yu Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiajia Du</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1903.00221 by other authors</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11864v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11864v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.optics" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11857v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T04:56:59Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T04:56:59Z</published>
    <title>Anderson transition and mobility edges on hyperbolic lattices</title>
    <summary>  Hyperbolic lattices, formed by tessellating the hyperbolic plane with regular
polygons, exhibit a diverse range of exotic physical phenomena beyond
conventional Euclidean lattices. Here, we investigate the impact of disorder on
hyperbolic lattices and reveal that the Anderson localization occurs at strong
disorder strength, accompanied by the presence of mobility edges. Taking the
hyperbolic $\{p,q\}=\{3,8\}$ and $\{p,q\}=\{4,8\}$ lattices as examples, we
employ finite-size scaling of both spectral statistics and the inverse
participation ratio to pinpoint the transition point and critical exponents.
Our findings indicate that the transition points tend to increase with larger
values of $\{p,q\}$ or curvature. In the limiting case of $\{\infty, q\}$, we
further determine its Anderson transition using the cavity method, drawing
parallels with the random regular graph. Our work lays the cornerstone for a
comprehensive understanding of Anderson transition and mobility edges in
non-Euclidean lattices.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tianyu Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yi Peng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yucheng Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haiping Hu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">7+6 pages, 5+3 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11857v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11857v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.dis-nn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.dis-nn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11853v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T04:44:32Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T04:44:32Z</published>
    <title>Re-exploring Control Strategies in a Non-Markovian Open Quantum System
  by Reinforcement Learning</title>
    <summary>  In this study, we reexamine a recent optimal control simulation targeting the
preparation of a superposition of two excited electronic states in the UV range
in a complex molecular system. We revisit this control from the perspective of
reinforcement learning, offering an efficient alternative to conventional
quantum control methods. The two excited states are addressable by orthogonal
polarizations and their superposition corresponds to a right or left
localization of the electronic density. The pulse duration spans tens of
femtoseconds to prevent excitation of higher excited bright states what leads
to a strong perturbation by the nuclear motions. We modify an open source
software by L. Giannelli et al., Phys. Lett. A, 434, 128054 (2022) that
implements reinforcement learning with Lindblad dynamics, to introduce
non-Markovianity of the surrounding either by timedependent rates or more
exactly by using the hierarchical equations of motion with the QuTiP-BoFiN
package. This extension opens the way to wider applications for non-Markovian
environments, in particular when the active system interacts with a highly
structured noise.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Amine Jaouadi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Etienne Mangaud</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michèle Desouter-Lecomte</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">18 pages, 11 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11853v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11853v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11840v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T04:12:56Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T04:12:56Z</published>
    <title>$k$-commutativity and measurement reduction for expectation values</title>
    <summary>  We introduce a notion of commutativity between operators on a tensor product
space, nominally Pauli strings on qubits, that interpolates between qubit-wise
commutativity and (full) commutativity. We apply this notion, which we call
$k$-commutativity, to measuring expectation values of observables in quantum
circuits and show a reduction in the number measurements at the cost of
increased circuit depth. Last, we discuss the asymptotic measurement complexity
of $k$-commutativity for several families of $n$-qubit Hamiltonians, showing
examples with $O(1)$, $O(\sqrt{n})$, and $O(n)$ scaling.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ben DalFavero</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rahul Sarkar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daan Camps</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicolas Sawaya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan LaRose</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">11 pages, 7 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11840v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11840v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14181v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T02:47:35Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T02:47:35Z</published>
    <title>Reversal of Orbital Hall Conductivity and Emergence of Tunable
  Topological Quantum States in Orbital Hall Insulator</title>
    <summary>  Recent findings indicate that orbital angular momentum (OAM) has the
capability to induce the intrinsic orbital Hall effect (OHE), which is
characterized by orbital Chern number in the orbital Hall insulator. Unlike the
spin-polarized channel in Quantum anomalous Hall insulator, the OAM is
valley-locked, posing challenges in manipulating the corresponding edge state.
Here we demonstrate the sign-reversal orbital Chern number through strain
engineering by combing the $k \cdot p$ model and first-principles calculation.
Under the manipulation of strain, we observe the transfer of non-zero OAM from
the valence band to the conduction band, aligning with the orbital contribution
in the electronic structure. Our investigation reveals that electrons and holes
with OAM exhibit opposing trajectories, resulting in a reversal of the orbital
Hall conductivity. Furthermore, we explore the topological quantum state
between the sign-reversible OHE.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Shilei Ji</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chuye Quan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruijia Yao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jianping Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xing'ao Li</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14181v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.14181v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11777v2</id>
    <updated>2024-01-10T11:52:52Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T01:17:35Z</published>
    <title>Field-free alignment and orientation of linear molecules by two-color
  trapezoidal laser pulses</title>
    <summary>  The field-free alignment and orientation of the linear molecule by the
two-color trapezoidal laser pulses were theoretically investigated. The
trapezoidal shape of a laser pulse allows to enhance the maximum alignment
degree for the same intensity and duration comparing to the conventional
Gaussian laser pulse. The alignment and orientation persist after the pulse for
both non-adiabatic and adiabatic regimes. While the maximum (during the pulse)
alignment degree quickly saturates and remains almost constant with the pulse
duration increase, the dependencies of the maximum (outside the laser pulse)
alignment and orientation degrees on the pulse duration show the clear periodic
structures in the adiabatic regime. The effect of the non-zero temperature is
also shown. Applying additional the monochromatic or two-color prepulse
increases the maximum orientation degree, but the application of the two-color
prepulse leads to a higher maximum orientation degree than the monochromatic
prepulse. The effect of the relative phase variation on the molecular
orientation in case of one and two pulses was also discussed.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Eugene A. Koval</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11777v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11777v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
