<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dti%3A%22quantum%20computing%22%20AND%20submittedDate%3A%5B202312180000%20TO%20202312182359%5D%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D40" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=ti:"quantum computing" AND submittedDate:[202312180000 TO 202312182359]&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=40</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/LD8tOE8TCyxidzOrkHdhO05GBmI</id>
  <updated>2024-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">5</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">40</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11673v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-18T19:30:26Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-18T19:30:26Z</published>
    <title>First quantum machine learning applications on an on-site
  room-temperature quantum computer</title>
    <summary>  We demonstrate - for the first time - the application of a quantum machine
learning (QML) algorithm on an on-site room-temperature quantum computer. A
two-qubit quantum computer installed at the Pawsey Supercomputing Centre in
Perth, Australia, is used to solve multi-class classification problems on
unseen, i.e. untrained, 2D data points. The underlying 1-qubit model is based
on the data re-uploading framework of the universal quantum classifier and was
trained on an ideal quantum simulator using the Adam optimiser. No noise models
or device-specific insights were used in the training process. The optimised
model was deployed to the quantum device by means of a single XYX decomposition
leading to three parameterised single qubit rotations. The results for
different classification problems are compared to the optimal results of an
ideal simulator. The room-temperature quantum computer achieves very high
classification accuracies, on par with ideal state vector simulations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nils Herrmann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mariam Akhtar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daanish Arya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marcus W. Doherty</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pascal Macha</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Florian Preis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stefan Prestel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael L. Walker</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">7 pages, 5 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11673v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11673v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11337v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-18T16:41:30Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-18T16:41:30Z</published>
    <title>Challenges for Reinforcement Learning in Quantum Computing</title>
    <summary>  Quantum computing (QC) in the current NISQ-era is still limited. To gain
early insights and advantages, hybrid applications are widely considered
mitigating those shortcomings. Hybrid quantum machine learning (QML) comprises
both the application of QC to improve machine learning (ML), and the
application of ML to improve QC architectures. This work considers the latter,
focusing on leveraging reinforcement learning (RL) to improve current QC
approaches. We therefore introduce various generic challenges arising from
quantum architecture search and quantum circuit optimization that RL algorithms
need to solve to provide benefits for more complex applications and
combinations of those. Building upon these challenges we propose a concrete
framework, formalized as a Markov decision process, to enable to learn policies
that are capable of controlling a universal set of quantum gates. Furthermore,
we provide benchmark results to assess shortcomings and strengths of current
state-of-the-art algorithms.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Philipp Altmann</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Adelina Bärligea</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonas Stein</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Kölle</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Gabor</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thomy Phan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Claudia Linnhoff-Popien</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">9 pages, 3 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11337v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11337v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11253v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-18T14:51:15Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-18T14:51:15Z</published>
    <title>Quantum Computing Inspired Iterative Refinement for Semidefinite
  Optimization</title>
    <summary>  Iterative Refinement (IR) is a classical computing technique for obtaining
highly precise solutions to linear systems of equations, as well as linear
optimization problems. In this paper, motivated by the limited precision of
quantum solvers, we develop the first IR scheme for solving semidefinite
optimization (SDO) problems and explore two major impacts of the proposed IR
scheme. First, we prove that the proposed IR scheme exhibits quadratic
convergence toward an optimal solution without any assumption on problem
characteristics. We also show that using IR with Quantum Interior Point Methods
(QIPMs) leads to exponential improvements in the worst-case overall running
time of QIPMs, compared to previous best-performing QIPMs. We also discuss how
the proposed IR scheme can be used with classical inexact SDO solvers, such as
classical inexact IPMs with conjugate gradient methods.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Mohammadhossein Mohammadisiahroudi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Augustino</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pouya Sampourmahani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tamás Terlaky</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11253v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11253v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="math.OC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.OC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11012v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-18T08:28:09Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-18T08:28:09Z</published>
    <title>Coupled cluster method tailored with quantum computing</title>
    <summary>  Introducing an active space approximation is inevitable for the quantum
computations of chemical systems. However, this approximation ignores the
electron correlations related to non-active orbitals. Here, we propose a
computational method for correcting quantum computing results using a
well-established classical theory called coupled cluster theory. Our approach
efficiently extracts the quantum state from a quantum device by computational
basis tomography. The extracted expansion coefficients of the quantum state are
embedded into the coupled cluster ansatz within the framework of the tailored
coupled cluster method. We demonstrate the performance of our method by
verifying the potential energy curves of LiH, H2O, and N2 with a
correlation-energy correction scheme. Our method demonstrates reasonable
potential energy curves even when the standard coupled cluster fails. The
sufficient numbers of measurements for tomography were also investigated.
Furthermore, this method successfully estimated the activation energy of the
Cope rearrangement reaction of 1,5-hexadiene together with perturbative triples
correction. These demonstrations suggest that our approach has the potential
for practical quantum chemical calculations using quantum computers.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Luca Erhart</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuichiro Yoshida</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Viktor Khinevich</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wataru Mizukami</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">12 pages, 8 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11012v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.11012v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10865v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-18T01:01:31Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-18T01:01:31Z</published>
    <title>Minimizing Photonic Cluster State Depth in Measurement-Based Quantum
  Computing</title>
    <summary>  Measurement-based quantum computing (MBQC) is a promising quantum computing
paradigm that performs computation through ``one-way'' measurements on
entangled quantum qubits. It is widely used in photonic quantum computing
(PQC), where the computation is carried out on photonic cluster states (i.e., a
2-D mesh of entangled photons). In MBQC-based PQC, the cluster state depth
(i.e., the length of one-way measurements) to execute a quantum circuit plays
an important role in the overall execution time and error. Thus, it is
important to reduce the cluster state depth. In this paper, we propose FMCC, a
compilation framework that employs dynamic programming to efficiently minimize
the cluster state depth. Experimental results on five representative quantum
algorithms show that FMCC achieves 53.6%, 60.6%, and 60.0% average depth
reductions in small, medium, and large qubit counts compared to the
state-of-the-art MBQC compilation frameworks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yingheng Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aditya Pawar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zewei Mo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Youtao Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jun Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xulong Tang</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.10865v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.10865v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
