<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dti%3A%22quantum%20computing%22%20AND%20submittedDate%3A%5B202312190000%20TO%20202312192359%5D%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D40" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=ti:"quantum computing" AND submittedDate:[202312190000 TO 202312192359]&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=40</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/FQZaJD+afdZYXf87zndpJzl3MOY</id>
  <updated>2024-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">4</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">40</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12613v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T21:36:07Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T21:36:07Z</published>
    <title>Toward coherent quantum computation of scattering amplitudes with a
  measurement-based photonic quantum processor</title>
    <summary>  In recent years, applications of quantum simulation have been developed to
study properties of strongly interacting theories. This has been driven by two
factors: on the one hand, needs from theorists to have access to physical
observables that are prohibitively difficult to study using classical
computing; on the other hand, quantum hardware becoming increasingly reliable
and scalable to larger systems. In this work, we discuss the feasibility of
using quantum optical simulation for studying scattering observables that are
presently inaccessible via lattice QCD and are at the core of the experimental
program at Jefferson Lab, the future Electron-Ion Collider, and other
accelerator facilities. We show that recent progress in measurement-based
photonic quantum computing can be leveraged to provide deterministic generation
of required exotic gates and implementation in a single photonic quantum
processor.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Raúl A. Briceño</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Robert G. Edwards</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Miller Eaton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Carlos González-Arciniegas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Olivier Pfister</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>George Siopsis</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">26 pages, 7 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12613v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12613v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-lat" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12427v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T18:56:03Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T18:56:03Z</published>
    <title>Enhancing quantum utility: simulating large-scale quantum spin chains on
  superconducting quantum computers</title>
    <summary>  We present the quantum simulation of the frustrated quantum
spin-$\frac{1}{2}$ antiferromagnetic Heisenberg spin chain with competing
nearest-neighbor $(J_1)$ and next-nearest-neighbor $(J_2)$ exchange
interactions in the real superconducting quantum computer with qubits ranging
up to 100. In particular, we implement, for the first time, the Hamiltonian
with the next-nearest neighbor exchange interaction in conjunction with the
nearest neighbor interaction on IBM's superconducting quantum computer and
carry out the time evolution of the spin chain by employing first-order
Trotterization. Furthermore, our novel implementation of second-order
Trotterization for the isotropic Heisenberg spin chain, involving only
nearest-neighbor exchange interaction, enables precise measurement of the
expectation values of staggered magnetization observable across a range of up
to 100 qubits. Notably, in both cases, our approach results in a constant
circuit depth in each Trotter step, independent of the initial number of
qubits. Our demonstration of the accurate measurement of expectation values for
the large-scale quantum system using superconducting quantum computers
designates the quantum utility of these devices for investigating various
properties of many-body quantum systems. This will be a stepping stone to
achieving the quantum advantage over classical ones in simulating quantum
systems before the fault tolerance quantum era.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Talal Ahmed Chowdhury</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kwangmin Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mahmud Ashraf Shamim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. L. Kabir</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Raza Sabbir Sufian</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">23 pages + references, 11 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12427v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12427v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-lat" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12386v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T18:18:51Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T18:18:51Z</published>
    <title>Quantum Equation of Motion with Orbital Optimization for Computing
  Molecular Properties in Near-Term Quantum Computing</title>
    <summary>  Determining the properties of molecules and materials is one of the premier
applications of quantum computing. A major question in the field is how to use
imperfect near-term quantum computers to solve problems of practical value.
Inspired by the recently developed variants of the quantum counterpart of the
equation-of-motion (qEOM) approach and the orbital-optimized variational
quantum eigensolver (oo-VQE), we present a quantum algorithm (oo-VQE-qEOM) for
the calculation of molecular properties by computing expectation values on a
quantum computer. We perform noise-free quantum simulations of BeH$_2$ in the
series of STO-3G/6-31G/6-31G* basis sets, H$_4$ and H$_2$O in 6-31G using an
active space of four electrons and four spatial orbitals (8 qubits) to evaluate
excitation energies, electronic absorption, and for twisted H$_4$, circular
dichroism spectra. We demonstrate that the proposed algorithm can reproduce the
results of conventional classical CASSCF calculations for these molecular
systems.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Phillip W. K. Jensen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Erik Rosendahl Kjellgren</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peter Reinholdt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Karl Michael Ziems</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sonia Coriani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Kongsted</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stephan P. A. Sauer</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">17+12 pages, 3 figures, 1 table; comments welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12386v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12386v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.comp-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12320v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-19T16:44:49Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-19T16:44:49Z</published>
    <title>Accurate harmonic vibrational frequencies for diatomic molecules via
  quantum computing</title>
    <summary>  During the noisy intermediate-scale quantum (NISQ) era, quantum computational
approaches refined to overcome the challenge of limited quantum resources are
highly valuable. However, the accuracy of the molecular properties predicted by
most of the quantum computations nowadays is still far off (not within chemical
accuracy) compared to their corresponding experimental data. Here, we propose a
promising qubit-efficient quantum computational approach to calculate the
harmonic vibrational frequencies of a large set of neutral closed-shell
diatomic molecules with results in great agreement with their experimental
data. To this end, we construct the accurate Hamiltonian using molecular
orbitals, derived from density functional theory to account for the electron
correlation and expanded in the Daubechies wavelet basis set to allow an
accurate representation in real space grid points, where an optimized compact
active space is further selected so that only a reduced small number of qubits
is sufficient to yield an accurate result. To justify the approach, we
benchmark the performance of the Hamiltonians spanned by the selected molecular
orbitals by first transforming the molecular Hamiltonians into qubit
Hamiltonians and then using the exact diagonalization method to calculate the
results, regarded as the best results achievable by quantum computation.
Furthermore, we show that the variational quantum circuit with the
chemistry-inspired UCCSD ansatz can achieve the same accuracy as the exact
diagonalization method except for systems whose Mayer bond order indices are
larger than 2. For those systems, we demonstrate that the heuristic
hardware-efficient RealAmplitudes ansatz, even with a shorter circuit depth,
can provide a significant improvement over the UCCSD ansatz, verifying that the
harmonic vibrational frequencies could be calculated accurately by quantum
computation in the NISQ era.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Shih-Kai Chou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jyh-Pin Chou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alice Hu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuan-Chung Cheng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hsi-Sheng Goan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043216</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043216" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">17 pages, 5 figures plus 11-page supplemental material</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Physical Review Research 5, 043216 (2023)</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12320v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12320v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
