<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dcat%3Aquant-ph%20AND%20submittedDate%3A%5B202312200000%20TO%20202312202359%5D%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D40" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=cat:quant-ph AND submittedDate:[202312200000 TO 202312202359]&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=40</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/qzgNop9Bit6/t0ATyc8eOYfKhBs</id>
  <updated>2024-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">54</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">40</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13483v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T23:31:53Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T23:31:53Z</published>
    <title>SQuADDS: A validated design database and simulation workflow for
  superconducting qubit design</title>
    <summary>  We present an open-source database of superconducting quantum device designs
that may be used as the starting point for customized devices. Each design can
be generated programmatically using the open-source Qiskit Metal package, and
simulated using finite-element electromagnetic solvers. We present a robust
workflow for achieving high accuracy on design simulations. Many designs in the
database are experimentally validated, showing excellent agreement between
simulated and measured parameters. Our database includes a front-end interface
that allows users to generate ``best-guess'' designs based on desired circuit
parameters. This project lowers the barrier to entry for research groups
seeking to make a new class of devices by providing them a well-characterized
starting point from which to refine their designs.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sadman Shanto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andre Kuo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Clark Miyamoto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Haimeng Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Vivek Maurya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Evangelos Vlachos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Malida Hecht</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chung Wa Shum</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Eli Levenson-Falk</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13483v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13483v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13473v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T22:48:38Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T22:48:38Z</published>
    <title>Accuracy vs Memory Advantage in the Quantum Simulation of Stochastic
  Processes</title>
    <summary>  Many inference scenarios rely on extracting relevant information from known
data in order to make future predictions. When the underlying stochastic
process satisfies certain assumptions, there is a direct mapping between its
exact classical and quantum simulators, with the latter asymptotically using
less memory. Here we focus on studying whether such quantum advantage persists
when those assumptions are not satisfied, and the model is doomed to have
imperfect accuracy. By studying the trade-off between accuracy and memory
requirements, we show that quantum models can reach the same accuracy with less
memory, or alternatively, better accuracy with the same memory. Finally, we
discuss the implications of this result for learning tasks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Leonardo Banchi</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13473v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13473v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.MP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13458v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T22:17:56Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T22:17:56Z</published>
    <title>Fourier Quantum Process Tomography</title>
    <summary>  The characterization of a quantum device is a crucial step in the development
of quantum experiments. This is accomplished via Quantum Process Tomography,
which combines the outcomes of different projective measurements to deliver a
possible reconstruction of the underlying process. The tomography is typically
performed by processing an overcomplete set of measurements and extracting the
process matrix from maximum-likelihood estimation. Here, we introduce a new
technique, referred to as Fourier Quantum Process Tomography, which requires a
reduced number of measurements, and benchmark its performance against the
standard maximum-likelihood approach. Fourier Quantum Process Tomography is
based on measuring probability distributions in two conjugate spaces for
different state preparations and projections. Exploiting the concept of phase
retrieval, our scheme achieves a complete and robust characterization of the
setup by processing a near-minimal set of measurements. We experimentally test
the technique on different space-dependent polarization transformations,
reporting average fidelities higher than 90% and significant computational
advantage.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Francesco Di Colandrea</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nazanin Dehghan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alessio D'Errico</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ebrahim Karimi</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13458v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13458v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13444v2</id>
    <updated>2024-01-08T17:19:50Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T21:36:09Z</published>
    <title>Optimal energy storage in the Tavis-Cummings quantum battery</title>
    <summary>  The Tavis-Cummings (TC) model, which serves as a natural physical realization
of a quantum battery, comprises $N_b$ atoms as battery cells that collectively
interact with a shared photon field, functioning as the charger, initially
containing $n_0$ photons. In this study, we introduce the invariant subspace
method to effectively represent the quantum dynamics of the TC battery. Our
findings indicate that in the limiting case of $n_0\!\gg\! N_b$ or $N_b\!\gg\!
n_0$, a distinct SU(2) symmetry emerges in the dynamics, thereby ensuring the
realization of optimal energy storage. We also establish a negative
relationship between the battery-charger entanglement and the energy storage
capacity. As a result, we demonstrate that the asymptotically optimal energy
storage can be achieved in the scenario where $N_b\!=\!n_0\!\gg\! 1$. Our
approach not only enhances our comprehension of the algebraic structure
inherent in the TC model but also contributes to the broader theoretical
framework of quantum batteries. Furthermore, it provides crucial insights into
the relation between energy transfer and quantum correlations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Hui-Yu Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hai-Long Shi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Qing-Kun Wan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kun Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiao-Hui Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wen-Li Yang</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012204</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012204" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">8 pages, 4 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Phys. Rev. A 109, 012204 (2024)</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13444v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13444v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13421v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T20:51:10Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T20:51:10Z</published>
    <title>Geometric signature of non-Markovian dynamics</title>
    <summary>  Non-Markovian effects of an open system dynamics are typically characterized
by non-monotonic information flows from the system to its environment or
information backflows from the environment to the system. By using a two-level
system (TLS) coupled to a dissipative single-mode cavity, we show that the
geometric decoherence of the open quantum system of interest can serve as a
reliable witness of non-Markovian dynamics. This geometric approach can also
reveal the finer details about the dynamics such as the time points where the
non-Markovian behaviors come into operation. Specifically, we show that the
divergence of the geometric decoherence factor of the TLS can be a sufficient
condition for the non-Markovian dynamics. Remarkably, it can even become a
necessary and sufficient condition in certain cases.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Da-Wei Luo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ting Yu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">6 pages, 3 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13421v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13421v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13420v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T20:50:54Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T20:50:54Z</published>
    <title>Ultraslow Growth of Number Entropy in an l-bit Model of Many-Body
  Localization</title>
    <summary>  We demonstrate that slow growth of the number entropy following a quench from
a local product state is consistent with many-body localization. To do this we
construct a random circuit l-bit model with exponentially localized l-bits and
exponentially decaying interactions between them. We observe an ultraslow
growth of the number entropy starting from a N\'eel state, saturating at a
value that grows with system size. This suggests that the observation of such
growth in microscopic models is not sufficient to rule out many-body
localization.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>David Aceituno Chávez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Claudia Artiaco</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas Klein Kvorning</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Loïc Herviou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jens H. Bardarson</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Main: 6 pages, 2 figures. Supplemental material: 6 pages, 6 figures,
  1 table, 1 video</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13420v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13420v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.dis-nn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.dis-nn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13419v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T20:44:18Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T20:44:18Z</published>
    <title>Entanglement Dynamics in Monitored Systems and the Role of Quantum Jumps</title>
    <summary>  Monitored quantum many-body systems display a rich pattern of entanglement
dynamics, which is unique to this non-unitary setting. This work studies the
effect of quantum jumps on the entanglement dynamics beyond the no-click limit
corresponding to a deterministic non-Hermitian evolution. We consider two
examples, a monitored SSH model and a quantum Ising chain, for which we show
the jumps have remarkably different effects on the entanglement despite having
the same statistics as encoded in their waiting-time distribution. To
understand this difference, we introduce a new metric, the statistics of
entanglement gain and loss due to jumps and non-Hermitian evolution. This
insight allows us to build a simple stochastic model of a random walk with
partial resetting, which reproduces the entanglement dynamics, and to dissect
the mutual role of jumps and non-Hermitian evolution on the entanglement
scaling. We demonstrate that significant deviations from the no-click limit
arise whenever quantum jumps strongly renormalize the non-Hermitian dynamics,
as in the case of the SSH model at weak monitoring or in the Ising chain at
large transverse field. On the other hand, we show that the weak monitoring
phase of the Ising chain leads to a robust sub-volume logarithmic phase due to
weakly renormalized non-Hermitian dynamics.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Youenn Le Gal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xhek Turkeshi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marco Schirò</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">16 + 5 pages, 10 + 4 figures. Comments are welcome!</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13419v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13419v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13408v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T20:23:32Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T20:23:32Z</published>
    <title>Testing Eigenstate Thermalization Hypothesis for Non-Abelian Gauge
  Theories</title>
    <summary>  We report on progress in full quantum understanding of thermalization in
non-Abelian gauge theories. Specifically, we test the eigenstate thermalization
hypothesis for (2+1)-dimensional SU(2) lattice gauge theory.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xiaojun Yao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lukas Ebner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Berndt Müller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andreas Schäfer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Clemens Seidl</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">4 pages, 4 figures, contribution to the proceedings of the 30th
  International Conference on Ultra-relativistic Nucleus-Nucleus Collisions
  (Quark Matter 2023)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13408v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13408v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-lat" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-lat" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="nucl-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13406v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T20:18:51Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T20:18:51Z</published>
    <title>A condition for the zero-error capacity of quantum channels</title>
    <summary>  In this paper, we present a condition for the zero-error capacity of quantum
channels. To achieve this result we first prove that the eigenvectors (or
eigenstates) common to the Kraus operators representing the quantum channel are
fixed points of the channel. From this fact and assuming that these Kraus
operators have at least two eigenstates in common and also considering that
every quantum channel has at least one fixed point, it is proved that the
zero-error capacity of the quantum channel is positive. Moreover, this
zero-error capacity condition is a lower bound for the zero-error capacity of
the quantum channel. This zero-error capacity condition of quantum channels has
a peculiar feature that it is easy to verify when one knows the Kraus operators
representing the quantum channel.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Marciel M. Oliveira</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Francisco M. de Assis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Micael A. Dias</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Four pages, conference paper</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13406v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13406v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.OA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13400v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T20:04:39Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T20:04:39Z</published>
    <title>SICs and the triangle group (3,3,3)</title>
    <summary>  The problem of existence of symmetric informationally-complete positive
operator-valued measures (SICs for short) in every dimension is known as
Zauner's conjecture and remains open to this day. Most of the known SIC
examples are constructed as an orbit of the Weyl-Heisenberg group action. It
appears that in these cases SICs are invariant under so-called canonical order
3 unitaries, which define automorphisms of the Weyl-Heisenberg group. In this
note we show that those order 3 unitaries appear in projective unitary
representations of the triangle group $(3,3,3)$. We give a full description of
such representations and show how it can be used to obtain results about the
structure of canonical order 3 unitaries. In particular, we present an
alternative way of proving the fact that any canonical order 3 unitary is
conjugate to Zauner's unitary if dimension $d&gt;3$ is prime.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Danylo Yakymenko</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13400v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13400v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.RT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="20C35, 81P15, 81R05" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13386v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T19:21:06Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T19:21:06Z</published>
    <title>Long-time Quantum Information Scrambling and Emergent Mereology</title>
    <summary>  Recent work by Zanardi et al. (arXiv:2212.14340) has associated each possible
partition of a quantum system with an operational subalgebra and proposed that
the short-time growth of the algebraic out-of-time-order-correlator
("$\mathcal{A}$-OTOC") is a suitable criterion to determine which partition
arises naturally from the system's unitary dynamics. We extend this work to the
long-time regime. Specifically, the long-time average of the $\mathcal{A}$-OTOC
serves as our metric of subsystem emergence. Under this framework, natural
system partitions are characterized by the tendency to minimally scramble
information over long time scales. We derive an analytic expression for the
$\mathcal{A}$-OTOC long-time average under the non-resonance condition. We then
consider several physical examples and perform minimization of this quantity
both analytically and numerically over relevant families of algebras. For
simple cases subject to the non-resonant condition, minimal $\mathcal{A}$-OTOC
long-time average is shown to be related to minimal entanglement of the
Hamiltonian eigenstates across the emergent system partition. Finally, we
conjecture and provide evidence for a general structure of the algebra that
minimizes the average for non-resonant Hamiltonians.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Faidon Andreadakis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emanuel Dallas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Paolo Zanardi</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Preliminary version, comments are welcome. 10+5 pages, 4 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13386v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13386v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13376v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T19:04:17Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T19:04:17Z</published>
    <title>Advantage of multi-partite entanglement for quantum cryptography over
  long and short ranged networks</title>
    <summary>  The increasing sophistication of available quantum networks has seen a
corresponding growth in the pursuit of multi-partite cryptographic protocols.
Whilst the use of multi-partite entanglement is known to offer an advantage in
certain abstractly motivated contexts, the quest to find practical advantage
scenarios is ongoing and substantial difficulties in generalising some
bi-partite security proofs still remain. We present rigorous results that
address both these challenges at the same time. First, we prove the security of
a variant of the GHZ state based secret sharing protocol against general
attacks, including participant attacks which break the security of the original
GHZ state scheme. We then identify parameters for a performance advantage over
realistic bottleneck networks. We show that whilst channel losses limit the
advantage region to short distances over direct transmission networks, the
addition of quantum repeaters unlocks the performance advantage of
multi-partite entanglement over point-to-point approaches for long distance
quantum cryptography.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Janka Memmen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jens Eisert</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Walk</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">19 pages, 10 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13376v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13376v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13374v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T19:03:23Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T19:03:23Z</published>
    <title>On the tensorial structure of general covariant quantum systems</title>
    <summary>  The definition of a quantum system requires a Hilbert space, a way to define
the dynamics, and an algebra of observables. The structure of the observable
algebra is related to a tensor product decomposition of the Hilbert space and
represents the composition of the system by subsystems. It has been remarked
that the Hamiltonian may determine this tensor product structure. Here we
observe that this fact may lead to questionable consequences in some cases, and
does extend to the more general background-independent case, where the
Hamiltonian is replaced by a Hamiltonian constraint. These observations
reinforces the idea that specifying the observables and the way they interplay
with the dynamics, is essential to define a quantum theory. We also reflect on
the general role that system decomposition has in the quantum theory.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Gabriel M. Carral</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Iñaki Garay</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Francesca Vidotto</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages, no figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13374v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13374v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.hist-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13350v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T19:00:02Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T19:00:02Z</published>
    <title>Improving fidelity of multi-qubit gates using hardware-level pulse
  parallelization</title>
    <summary>  Quantum computation holds the promise of solving computational problems which
are believed to be classically intractable. However, in practice, quantum
devices are still limited by their relatively short coherence times and
imperfect circuit-hardware mapping. In this work, we present the
parallelization of pre-calibrated pulses at the hardware level as an
easy-to-implement strategy to optimize quantum gates. Focusing on $R_{ZX}$
gates, we demonstrate that such parallelization leads to improved fidelity and
gate time reduction, when compared to serial concatenation. As measured by
Cycle Benchmarking, our most modest fidelity gain was from 98.16(7)% to
99.15(3)% for the application of two $R_{ZX}(\pi/2)$ gates with one shared
qubit. We show that this strategy can be applied to other gates like the CNOT
and CZ, and it may benefit tasks such as Hamiltonian simulation problems,
amplitude amplification, and error-correction codes.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sagar Silva Pratapsi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Diogo Cruz</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13350v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13350v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13343v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T19:00:01Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T19:00:01Z</published>
    <title>Closed-form expressions for smeared bi-distributions of a massless
  scalar field: non-perturbative and asymptotic results in relativistic quantum
  information</title>
    <summary>  Using spacetime Gaussian test functions, we find closed-form expressions for
the smeared Wightman function, Feynman propagator, retarded and advanced
Green's functions, causal propagator and symmetric propagator of a massless
scalar field in the vacuum of Minkowski spacetime. We apply our results to
localized quantum systems which interact with a quantum field in Gaussian
spacetime regions and study different relativistic quantum information
protocols. In the protocol of entanglement harvesting, we find a closed-form
expression for the entanglement that can be acquired by probes which interact
in Gaussian spacetime regions and obtain asymptotic results for the protocol.
We also revisit the case of two gapless detectors and show that the detectors
can become entangled if there is two-way signalling between their interaction
regions, providing closed-form expressions for the detectors' final state.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>T. Rick Perche</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">14 pages, 2 figures, 1 appendix. Revtex 4-2</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13343v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13343v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13282v2</id>
    <updated>2024-01-01T20:48:32Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T18:59:15Z</published>
    <title>Estimating Trotter Approximation Errors to Optimize Hamiltonian
  Partitioning for Lower Eigenvalue Errors</title>
    <summary>  One of the ways to encode many-body Hamiltonians on a quantum computer to
obtain their eigen-energies through Quantum Phase Estimation is by means of the
Trotter approximation. There were several ways proposed to assess the quality
of this approximation based on estimating the norm of the difference between
the exact and approximate evolution operators. Here, we would like to explore
how these different error estimates are correlated with each other and whether
they can be good predictors for the true Trotter approximation error in finding
eigenvalues. For a set of small molecular systems we calculated the exact
Trotter approximation errors of the first order Trotter formulas for the ground
state electronic energies. Comparison of these errors with previously used
upper bounds show almost no correlation over the systems and various
Hamiltonian partitionings. On the other hand, building the Trotter
approximation error estimation based on perturbation theory up to a second
order in the time-step for eigenvalues provides estimates with very good
correlations with the Trotter approximation errors. The developed perturbative
estimates can be used for practical time-step and Hamiltonian partitioning
selection protocols, which are paramount for an accurate assessment of
resources needed for the estimation of energy eigenvalues under a target
accuracy.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Luis A. Martínez-Martínez</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Prathami Divakar Kamath</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Artur F. Izmaylov</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">3 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13282v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13282v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00860v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T18:40:37Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T18:40:37Z</published>
    <title>Optical tweezer generation using automated alignment and adaptive optics</title>
    <summary>  Recent progress in quantum technologies with ultracold atoms has been
propelled by spatially fine-tuned control of lasers and diffraction-limited
imaging. The state-of-the-art precision of optical alignment to achieve this
fine-tuning is reaching the limits of manual control. Here, we show how to
automate this process. One of the elementary techniques of manual alignment of
optics is cross-walking of laser beams. Here, we generalize this technique to
multi-variable cross-walking. Mathematically, this is a variant of the
well-known Alternating Minimization (AM) algorithm in convex optimization and
is closely related to the Gauss-Seidel algorithm. Therefore, we refer to our
multi-variable cross-walking algorithm as the modified AM algorithm. While
cross-walking more than two variables manually is challenging, one can do this
easily for machine-controlled variables. We apply this algorithm to
mechanically align high numerical aperture (NA) objectives and show that we can
produce high-quality diffraction-limited tweezers and point spread functions
(PSF). After a rudimentary coarse alignment, the algorithm takes about 1 hour
to align the optics to produce high-quality tweezers. Moreover, we use the same
algorithm to optimize the shape of a deformable mirror along with the
mechanical variables and show that it can be used to correct for optical
aberrations produced, for example, by glass thickness when producing tweezers
and imaging point sources. The shape of the deformable mirror is parametrized
using the first 14 non-trivial Zernike polynomials, and the corresponding
coefficients are optimized together with the mechanical alignment variables. We
show PSF with a Strehl ratio close to 1 and tweezers with a Strehl ratio &gt;0.8.
The algorithm demonstrates exceptional robustness, effectively operating in the
presence of significant mechanical fluctuations induced by a noisy environment.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Bharath Hebbe Madhusudhana</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Karatzyna Krzyzanowska</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Malcolm Boshier</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">13 pages, 11 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.00860v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.00860v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.quant-gas" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.quant-gas" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.optics" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13250v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T18:25:15Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T18:25:15Z</published>
    <title>The role of data embedding in equivariant quantum convolutional neural
  networks</title>
    <summary>  Geometric deep learning refers to the scenario in which the symmetries of a
dataset are used to constrain the parameter space of a neural network and thus,
improve their trainability and generalization. Recently this idea has been
incorporated into the field of quantum machine learning, which has given rise
to equivariant quantum neural networks (EQNNs). In this work, we investigate
the role of classical-to-quantum embedding on the performance of equivariant
quantum convolutional neural networks (EQCNNs) for the classification of
images. We discuss the connection between the data embedding method and the
resulting representation of a symmetry group and analyze how changing
representation affects the expressibility of an EQCNN. We numerically compare
the classification accuracy of EQCNNs with three different basis-permuted
amplitude embeddings to the one obtained from a non-equivariant quantum
convolutional neural network (QCNN). Our results show that all the EQCNNs
achieve higher classification accuracy than the non-equivariant QCNN for small
numbers of training iterations, while for large iterations this improvement
crucially depends on the used embedding. It is expected that the results of
this work can be useful to the community for a better understanding of the
importance of data embedding choice in the context of geometric quantum machine
learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sreetama Das</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stefano Martina</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Filippo Caruso</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">9 pages, 7 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13250v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13250v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.ET" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13246v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T18:22:42Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T18:22:42Z</published>
    <title>A refinement of the argument of local realism versus quantum mechanics
  by algorithmic randomness</title>
    <summary>  The notion of probability plays a crucial role in quantum mechanics. It
appears in quantum mechanics as the Born rule. In modern mathematics which
describes quantum mechanics, however, probability theory means nothing other
than measure theory, and therefore any operational characterization of the
notion of probability is still missing in quantum mechanics. In our former
works [K. Tadaki, arXiv:1804.10174], based on the toolkit of algorithmic
randomness, we presented a refinement of the Born rule, called the principle of
typicality, for specifying the property of results of measurements in an
operational way. In this paper, we make an application of our framework to the
argument of local realism versus quantum mechanics for refining it, in order to
demonstrate how properly our framework works in practical problems in quantum
mechanics.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kohtaro Tadaki</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">This work is a substantial extension of a preliminary paper of the
  author [arXiv:1804.10174] which appeared without peer review in: Masahiko
  Sakai (ed.), New Trends in Algorithms and Theory of Computation, RIMS
  Kokyuroku, No.2154, pp.27-53, April 2020. Available at
  http://hdl.handle.net/2433/255108. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1909.02854</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13246v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13246v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13241v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T18:08:25Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T18:08:25Z</published>
    <title>Deterministic Ansätze for the Measurement-based Variational Quantum
  Eigensolver</title>
    <summary>  Measurement-based quantum computing (MBQC) is a promising approach to
reducing circuit depth in noisy intermediate-scale quantum algorithms such as
the Variational Quantum Eigensolver (VQE). Unlike gate-based computing, MBQC
employs local measurements on a preprepared resource state, offering a
trade-off between circuit depth and qubit count. Ensuring determinism is
crucial to MBQC, particularly in the VQE context, as a lack of flow in
measurement patterns leads to evaluating the cost function at irrelevant
locations. This study introduces MBVQE-ans\"atze that respect determinism and
resemble the widely used problem-agnostic hardware-efficient VQE ansatz. We
evaluate our approach using ideal simulations on the Schwinger Hamiltonian and
$XY$-model and perform experiments on IBM hardware with an adaptive measurement
capability. In our use case, we find that ensuring determinism works better via
postselection than by adaptive measurements at the expense of increased
sampling cost. Additionally, we propose an efficient MBQC-inspired method to
prepare the resource state, specifically the cluster state, on hardware with
heavy-hex connectivity, requiring a single measurement round, and implement
this scheme on quantum computers with $27$ and $127$ qubits. We observe notable
improvements for larger cluster states, although direct gate-based
implementation achieves higher fidelity for smaller instances.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Anna Schroeder</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthias Heller</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mariami Gachechiladze</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">17 pages, 7 figures, comments welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13241v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13241v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13233v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T17:57:17Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T17:57:17Z</published>
    <title>Unified Framework for Open Quantum Dynamics with Memory</title>
    <summary>  Studies of the dynamics of a quantum system coupled to a bath are typically
performed by utilizing the Nakajima-Zwanzig memory kernel (${\mathcal{K}}$) or
the influence functions ($\mathbf{{I}}$), especially when the dynamics exhibit
memory effects (i.e., non-Markovian). Despite their significance, the formal
connection between the memory kernel and the influence functions has not been
explicitly made. We reveal their relation through the observation of a
diagrammatic structure underlying the system propagator, $\mathbf{{I}}$, and
${\mathcal{K}}$. Based on this, we propose a non-perturbative, diagrammatic
approach to construct ${\mathcal{K}}$ from $\mathbf{{I}}$ for (driven) systems
interacting with harmonic baths without the use of any projection-free dynamics
inputs required by standard approaches. With this construction, we also show
how approximate path integral methods can be understood in terms of approximate
memory kernels. Furthermore, we demonstrate a Hamiltonian learning procedure to
extract the bath spectral density from a set of reduced system trajectories
obtained experimentally or by numerically exact methods, opening new avenues in
quantum sensing and engineering. The insights we provide in this work will
significantly advance the understanding of non-Markovian dynamics, and they
will be an important stepping stone for theoretical and experimental
developments in this area.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Felix Ivander</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lachlan P. Lindoy</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Joonho Lee</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Comments and questions welcome!</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13233v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13233v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13221v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T17:39:22Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T17:39:22Z</published>
    <title>Robust atom-photon gate for quantum information processing</title>
    <summary>  We propose a scheme for two-qubit gates between a flying photon and an atom
in a cavity. The atom-photon gate setup consists of a cavity and a Mach-Zehnder
interferometer with doubly degenerate ground and excited state energy levels
mediating the atom-light interaction. We provide an error analysis of the gate
and model important errors, including spatial mode mismatch between the photon
and the cavity, spontaneous emission, cavity losses, detunings, and random
fluctuations of the cavity parameters and frequencies. Error analysis shows
that the gate protocol is more robust against experimental errors compared to
previous atom-photon gates and achieves higher fidelity.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Omar Nagib</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. Huft</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>A. Safari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Saffman</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">6 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13221v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13221v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.atom-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13214v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T17:31:19Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T17:31:19Z</published>
    <title>A pedagogical introduction to continuously monitored quantum systems and
  measurement-based feedback</title>
    <summary>  In this manuscript we present a pedagogical introduction to continuously
monitored quantum systems. We start by giving a simplified derivation of the
Markovian master equation in Lindblad form, in the spirit of collision models
and input-output theory, which describes the unconditional dynamics of a
continuously monitored system. The same formalism is then exploited to derive
stochastic master equations that describe the conditional dynamics. We focus on
the two most paradigmatic examples of continuous monitoring: continuous
photodetection, leading to a discontinuous dynamics with "quantum jumps", and
continuous homodyne measurements, leading to a diffusive dynamics. We then
present a derivation of feedback master equations that describe the dynamics
(either conditional or unconditional) when the continuous measurement
photocurrents are fed back to the system as a linear driving Hamiltonian, a
paradigm known as linear Markovian feedback. In the second part of the
manuscript we focus on continuous-variable Gaussian systems: we first present
the equations for first and second moments describing the dynamics under
continuous general-dyne measurements, and we then discuss in more detail the
conditional and unconditional dynamics under Markovian and state-based
feedback.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Francesco Albarelli</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Marco G. Genoni</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1016/j.physleta.2023.129260</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physleta.2023.129260" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Tutorial paper based on the lecture notes for the course "Coherence
  and control of quantum systems" taught by MGG at the University of Milan and
  submitted to the special issue "Foundations and applications of Quantum
  Optics" of Physics Letters A related to the Central European Workshop on
  Quantum Optics 2023</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Phys. Lett. A 494, 129260 (2024)</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13214v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13214v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13213v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T17:28:47Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T17:28:47Z</published>
    <title>Quantum transition probability in convex sets and self-dual cones</title>
    <summary>  The interplay between the algebraic structure (operator algebras) for the
quantum observables and the convex structure of the state space has been
explored for a long time and most advanced results are due to Alfsen and
Shultz. Here we present a more elementary approach with a more generic
structure for the observables, which focuses on the transition probability of
the quantum logical atoms. The binary case gives rise to the generalized qubit
models and was fully developed in a preceding paper. Here we consider any case
with finite information capacity (binary means that the information capacity is
2). A novel geometric property that makes any compact convex set a matching
state space is presented. Generally, the transition probability is not
symmetric; if it is symmetric, we get an inner product and a self-dual cone.
The emerging mathematical structure comes close to the Euclidean Jordan
algebras and becomes a new mathematical model for a potential extension of
quantum theory.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Gerd Niestegge</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">23 pages, 3 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13213v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13213v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.FA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.MP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.OA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13206v4</id>
    <updated>2024-01-11T16:17:29Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T17:23:11Z</published>
    <title>Polylogarithmic-depth controlled-NOT gates without ancilla qubits</title>
    <summary>  Controlled operations are fundamental building blocks of quantum algorithms.
Decomposing $n$-control-NOT gates ($C^n(X)$) into arbitrary single-qubit and
CNOT gates, is a crucial but non-trivial task. This study introduces $C^n(X)$
circuits outperforming previous methods in the asymptotic and non-asymptotic
regimes. Three distinct decompositions are presented: an exact one using one
borrowed ancilla with a circuit depth $\Theta\left(\log(n)^{3}\right)$, an
approximating one without ancilla qubits with a circuit depth $\mathcal O
\left(\log(n)^{3}\log(1/\epsilon)\right)$ and an exact one with an
adjustable-depth circuit which decreases with the number $m\leq n$ of ancilla
qubits available as $O(log(2n/m)^3+log(m/2))$. The resulting exponential
speedup is likely to have a substantial impact on fault-tolerant quantum
computing by improving the complexities of countless quantum algorithms with
applications ranging from quantum chemistry to physics, finance and quantum
machine learning.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Baptiste Claudon</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Julien Zylberman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>César Feniou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Fabrice Debbasch</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alberto Peruzzo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jean-Philip Piquemal</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13206v4" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13206v4" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13191v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T17:02:19Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T17:02:19Z</published>
    <title>Transmuted spectrum-generating algebras and detectable parastatistics of
  the Superconformal Quantum Mechanics</title>
    <summary>  In a recent paper (Balbino-de Freitas-Rana-FT, arXiv:2309.00965) we proved
that the supercharges of the supersymmetric quantum mechanics can be
statistically transmuted and accommodated into a $Z_2^n$-graded parastatistics.
In this talk I derive the $6=1+2+3$ transmuted spectrum-generating algebras
(whose respective $Z_2^n$ gradings are $n=0,1,2$) of the ${\cal N}=2$
Superconformal Quantum Mechanics. These spectrum-generating algebras allow to
compute, in the corresponding multiparticle sectors of the de
Alfaro-Fubini-Furlan deformed oscillator, the degeneracies of each energy
level. The levels induced by the $Z_2\times Z_2$-graded paraparticles cannot be
reproduced by the ordinary bosons/fermions statistics. This implies the
theoretical detectability of the $Z_2\times Z_2$-graded parastatistics.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Francesco Toppan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1088/1742-6596/2667/1/012014</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2667/1/012014" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">7 pages; in the proceedings of XII International Symposium on Quantum
  Theory and Symmetries - QTS12, Prague, July 2023</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 2667 (2023) 012014</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13191v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13191v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.MP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13185v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T16:54:05Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T16:54:05Z</published>
    <title>Measurement-based quantum computation from Clifford quantum cellular
  automata</title>
    <summary>  Measurement-based quantum computation (MBQC) is a paradigm for quantum
computation where computation is driven by local measurements on a suitably
entangled resource state. In this work we show that MBQC is related to a model
of quantum computation based on Clifford quantum cellular automata (CQCA).
Specifically, we show that certain MBQCs can be directly constructed from CQCAs
which yields a simple and intuitive circuit model representation of MBQC in
terms of quantum computation based on CQCA. We apply this description to
construct various MBQC-based Ans\"atze for parameterized quantum circuits,
demonstrating that the different Ans\"atze may lead to significantly different
performances on different learning tasks. In this way, MBQC yields a family of
Hardware-efficient Ans\"atze that may be adapted to specific problem settings
and is particularly well suited for architectures with translationally
invariant gates such as neutral atoms.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Hendrik Poulsen Nautrup</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hans J. Briegel</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">16 pages, 12 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13185v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13185v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.ET" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13135v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T15:56:31Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T15:56:31Z</published>
    <title>Accelerated adiabatic passage of a single electron spin qubit in quantum
  dots</title>
    <summary>  Adiabatic processes can keep the quantum system in its instantaneous
eigenstate, which is robust to noises and dissipation. However, it is limited
by sufficiently slow evolution. Here, we experimentally demonstrate the
transitionless quantum driving (TLQD) of the shortcuts to adiabaticity (STA) in
gate-defined semiconductor quantum dots (QDs) to greatly accelerate the
conventional adiabatic passage for the first time. For a given efficiency of
quantum state transfer, the acceleration can be more than 2-fold. The dynamic
properties also prove that the TLQD can guarantee fast and high-fidelity
quantum state transfer. In order to compensate for the diabatic errors caused
by dephasing noises, the modified TLQD is proposed and demonstrated in
experiment by enlarging the width of the counter-diabatic drivings. The
benchmarking shows that the state transfer fidelity of 97.8% can be achieved.
This work will greatly promote researches and applications about quantum
simulations and adiabatic quantum computation based on the gate-defined QDs.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xiao-Fei Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuta Matsumoto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Takafumi Fujita</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Arne Ludwig</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andreas D. Wieck</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Akira Oiwa</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">6 pages, 3 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13135v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13135v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mes-hall" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13123v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T15:44:15Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T15:44:15Z</published>
    <title>Investigating techniques to optimise the layout of turbines in a
  windfarm using a quantum computer</title>
    <summary>  We study the optimal placement of wind turbines within a windfarm to maximize
the power produced by mapping the system to a Quadratic Unconstrained Binary
Optimisation (QUBO) problem. We investigate solving the resulting QUBO problem
using the Variational Quantum Eigensolver (VQE) on a quantum computer simulator
and compare the results to those from two classical optimisation methods:
simulated annealing and the Gurobi solver. The maximum grid size we study is 4
$\times$ 4, which requires 16 qubits.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>James Hancock</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthew J. Craven</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Craig McNeile</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Davide Vadacchino</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13123v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13123v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13111v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T15:30:55Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T15:30:55Z</published>
    <title>State Expansion of a Levitated Nanoparticle in a Dark Harmonic Potential</title>
    <summary>  Levitated nanoparticles in vacuum are prime candidates for generating
macroscopic quantum superposition states of massive objects. Most protocols for
preparing these states necessitate coherent expansion beyond the scale of the
zero-point motion to produce sufficiently delocalized and pure phase-space
distributions. Here, we spatially expand and subsequently recontract the
thermal state of a levitated nanoparticle by modifying the stiffness of the
trap holding the particle. We achieve state-expansion factors of 25 in standard
deviation for a particle initially feedback-cooled to a center-of-mass thermal
state of \SI{155}{\milli\kelvin}. Our method relies on a hybrid scheme
combining an optical trap, for cooling and measuring the particle's motion,
with a Paul trap for expanding its state. Consequently, state expansion occurs
devoid of measurement backaction from photon recoil, making this approach
suitable for coherent wavefunction expansion in future experiments.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Bonvin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Louisiane Devaud</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Massimiliano Rossi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrei Militaru</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lorenzo Dania</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dmitry S. Bykov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Oriol Romero-Isart</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tracy E. Northup</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lukas Novotny</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Frimmer</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13111v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13111v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13063v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T14:42:05Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T14:42:05Z</published>
    <title>Microscopic theory of exciton-polariton model involving multiple
  molecules: Macroscopic quantum electrodynamics formulation and essence of
  direct intermolecular interactions</title>
    <summary>  Cavity quantum electrodynamics (CQED) and its extensions are widely used for
the description of exciton-polariton systems. However, the exciton-polariton
models based on CQED vary greatly within different contexts. One of the most
significant discrepancies among these CQED models is whether one should include
direct intermolecular interactions in the CQED Hamiltonian. To answer this
question, in this article, we derive an effective dissipative CQED model
including free-space dipole-dipole interactions (CQED-DDI) from a microscopic
Hamiltonian based on macroscopic quantum electrodynamics. Dissipative CQED-DDI
successfully captures the nature of vacuum fluctuations in dielectric media and
separates it into the free-space effects and the dielectric-induced effects.
The former include spontaneous emissions, dephasings and dipole-dipole
interactions in free space; the latter include exciton-polariton interactions
and photonic losses due to dielectric media. We apply dissipative CQED-DDI to
investigate the exciton-polariton dynamics (the population dynamics of
molecules above a plasmonic surface) and compare the results with those based
on the methods proposed by several previous studies. We find that direct
intermolecular interactions are a crucial element when employing CQED-like
models to study exciton-polariton systems involving multiple molecules.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yi-Ting Chuang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Liang-Yan Hsu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13063v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13063v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13037v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T14:02:42Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T14:02:42Z</published>
    <title>Quantum Observables of Quantized Fluxes</title>
    <summary>  While it has become widely appreciated that defining (higher) gauge theories
requires, in addition to ordinary phase space data, also "flux quantization"
laws in generalized differential cohomology, there has been little discussion
of the general rules, if any, for lifting Poisson-brackets of
(flux-)observables and their quantization from traditional phase spaces to the
resulting higher moduli stacks of flux-quantized gauge fields.
  In this short note, we present a systematic analysis of (i) the canonical
quantization of flux observables in Yang-Mills theory and (ii) of valid flux
quantization laws in abelian Yang-Mills, observing (iii) that the resulting
topological quantum observables form the homology Pontrjagin algebra of the
loop space of the moduli space of flux-quantized gauge fields.
  This is remarkable because the homology Ponrjagin algebra on loops of moduli
makes immediate sense in broad generality for higher and non-abelian
(non-linearly coupled) gauge fields, such as for the C-field in 11d
supergravity, where it recovers the quantum effects previously discussed in the
context of "Hypothesis H".
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Hisham Sati</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Urs Schreiber</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">20 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13037v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13037v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.AT" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.DG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.MP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13036v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T14:00:41Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T14:00:41Z</published>
    <title>Quantum State Compression Shadow</title>
    <summary>  Quantum state readout serves as the cornerstone of quantum information
processing, exerting profound influence on quantum communication, computation,
and metrology. In this study, we introduce an innovative readout architecture
called Compression Shadow (CompShadow), which transforms the conventional
readout paradigm by compressing multi-qubit states into single-qubit shadows
before measurement. Compared to direct measurements of the initial quantum
states, CompShadow achieves comparable accuracy in amplitude and observable
expectation estimation while consuming similar measurement resources.
Furthermore, its implementation on near-term quantum hardware with
nearest-neighbor coupling architectures is straightforward. Significantly,
CompShadow brings forth novel features, including the complete suppression of
correlated readout noise, fundamentally reducing the quantum hardware demands
for readout. It also facilitates the exploration of multi-body system
properties through single-qubit probes and opens the door to designing quantum
communication protocols with exponential loss suppression. Our findings mark
the emergence of a new era in quantum state readout, setting the stage for a
revolutionary leap in quantum information processing capabilities.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chen Ding</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xiao-Yue Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shuo Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wan-Su Bao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>He-Liang Huang</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13036v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13036v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13020v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T13:40:17Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T13:40:17Z</published>
    <title>Quantum multi-anomaly detection</title>
    <summary>  A source assumed to prepare a specified reference state sometimes prepares an
anomalous one. We address the task of identifying these anomalous states in a
series of $n$ preparations with $k$ anomalies. We analyse the minimum-error
protocol and the zero-error (unambiguous) protocol and obtain closed
expressions for the success probability when both reference and anomalous
states are known to the observer and anomalies can appear equally likely in any
position of the preparation series. We find the solution using results from
association schemes theory. In particular we use the Johnson association scheme
which arises naturally from the Gram matrix of this problem. We also study the
regime of large $n$ and obtain the expression of the success probability that
is non-vanishing. Finally, we address the case in which the observer is blind
to the reference and the anomalous states. This scenario requires an universal
protocol for which we prove that in the asymptotic limit the success
probability correspond to average of the known state scenario.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Santiago Llorens</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gael Sentís</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ramon Muñoz-Tapia</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">9 pages, 4 figures, comments are welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13020v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13020v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13003v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T13:10:17Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T13:10:17Z</published>
    <title>Spectrality in convex sequential effect algebras</title>
    <summary>  For convex and sequential effect algebras, we study spectrality in the sense
of Foulis. We show that under additional conditions (strong archimedeanity,
closedness in norm and a certain monotonicity property of the sequential
product), such effect algebra is spectral if and only if every maximal
commutative subalgebra is monotone $\sigma$-complete. Two previous results on
existence of spectral resolutions in this setting are shown to require stronger
assumptions.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Anna Jenčová</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sylvia Pulmannová</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:doi xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10.1007/s10773-023-05431-8</arxiv:doi>
    <link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10773-023-05431-8" rel="related"/>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">18 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:2111.02166</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Int J Theor Phys 62, 193 (2023)</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.13003v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.13003v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.FA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="math.RA" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12986v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T12:44:35Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T12:44:35Z</published>
    <title>Quadrature squeezing enhances Wigner negativity in a mechanical Duffing
  oscillator</title>
    <summary>  Generating macroscopic non-classical quantum states is a long-standing
challenge in physics. Anharmonic dynamics is an essential ingredient to
generate these states, but for large mechanical systems, the effect of the
anharmonicity tends to become negligible compared to decoherence. As a possible
solution to this challenge, we propose to use a motional squeezed state as a
resource to effectively enhance the anharmonicity. We analyze the production of
negativity in the Wigner distribution of a quantum anharmonic resonator
initially in a squeezed state. We find that initial squeezing enhances the rate
at which negativity is generated. We also analyze the effect of two common
sources of decoherence, namely energy damping and dephasing, and find that the
detrimental effects of energy damping are suppressed by strong squeezing. In
the limit of large squeezing, which is needed for state-of-the-art systems, we
find good approximations for the Wigner function. Our analysis is significant
for current experiments attempting to prepare macroscopic mechanical systems in
genuine quantum states. We provide an overview of several experimental
platforms featuring nonlinear behaviors and low levels of decoherence. In
particular, we discuss the feasibility of our proposal with carbon nanotubes
and levitated nanoparticles.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christian A. Rosiek</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Massimiliano Rossi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Albert Schliesser</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anders S. Sørensen</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12986v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12986v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14190v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T12:40:00Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T12:40:00Z</published>
    <title>Machine Learning for Anomaly Detection in Particle Physics</title>
    <summary>  The detection of out-of-distribution data points is a common task in particle
physics. It is used for monitoring complex particle detectors or for
identifying rare and unexpected events that may be indicative of new phenomena
or physics beyond the Standard Model. Recent advances in Machine Learning for
anomaly detection have encouraged the utilization of such techniques on
particle physics problems. This review article provides an overview of the
state-of-the-art techniques for anomaly detection in particle physics using
machine learning. We discuss the challenges associated with anomaly detection
in large and complex data sets, such as those produced by high-energy particle
colliders, and highlight some of the successful applications of anomaly
detection in particle physics experiments.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Vasilis Belis</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Patrick Odagiu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thea Klæboe Årrestad</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Invited review article, Reviews in Physics</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.14190v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.14190v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.data-an" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.data-an" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-ex" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12974v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T12:31:29Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T12:31:29Z</published>
    <title>Nanoparticle Interferometer by Throw and Catch</title>
    <summary>  Matter-wave interferometry with increasingly larger masses could pave the way
to understanding the nature of wavefunction collapse, the quantum to classical
transition or even how an object in a spatial superposition interacts with its
gravitational field. In order to improve upon the current mass record, it is
necessary to move into the nano-particle regime. In this paper we provide a
design for a nano-particle Talbot-Lau matter-wave interferometer that
circumvents the practical challenges of previously proposed designs. We present
simulations of the expected fringe patterns that such an interferometer would
produce, considering all major sources of decoherence. We discuss the practical
challenges involved in building such an experiment as well as some preliminary
experimental results to illustrate the proposed measurement scheme. We show
that such a design is suitable for seeing interference fringes with $10^6$amu
SiO$_2$ particles, and that this design can be extended to even $10^8$amu
particles by using flight times below the typical Talbot time of the system.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jakub Wardak</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tiberius Georgescu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Giulio Gasbarri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alessio Belenchia</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hendrik Ulbricht</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12974v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12974v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12956v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T11:55:05Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T11:55:05Z</published>
    <title>Restrictions to realize multiport quantum dense coding in a many-body
  quantum spin system with two- and three-body interactions</title>
    <summary>  Quantum information with many-body quantum spin systems has, from time to
time, given intriguing and intuitive outcomes to our understanding of multiport
quantum communications. We identify that in an anisotropic many-body quantum
spin system with two- and three-body interactions, when its two-spin subsystems
are all negative under partial transpose, one can restrict this system for
realizing only the multiport quantum dense coding protocol which has $(N-1)$
senders and a single receiver. All other single and multi channel dense coding
protocols will have quantum dense coding capacities less than that of their
respective classical capacities. We characterize the multiport quantum dense
coding capacity with $(N-1)$ senders and a single receiver for this system with
respect to its system parameters. We also define a magnetic field averaged
dense coding capacity for this system, which allows us to comprehensively
capture the influence of the entire range of external applied magnetic field
and characterize its variation with respect to other system parameters.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>P. Kiran</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hemant Shreepad Hegde</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Harsha Miriam Reji</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>R. Prabhu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">9 pages, 5 figures, RevTeX4-2</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12956v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12956v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12941v1</id>
    <updated>2023-12-20T11:37:12Z</updated>
    <published>2023-12-20T11:37:12Z</published>
    <title>Order-by-disorder in the antiferromagnetic long-range transverse-field
  Ising model on the ruby lattice</title>
    <summary>  We demonstrate that geometric frustration and long-range interactions both
promote order-by-disorder in the antiferromagnetic transverse-field Ising model
on the ruby lattice. To this end we investigate the quantum phase diagram for
truncated $J_1$-$J_2$-$J_3$ Ising interactions. In the low-field limit we
derive an effective quantum dimer model, analyzing how the extensive
ground-state degeneracy at zero field is lifted by two distinct
order-by-disorder scenarios. We support our analysis by studying the
gap-closing of the high-field phase using series expansions. For $J_2&gt;J_3$, we
find an emergent clock-ordered phase at low fields, stabilized by resonating
plaquettes, and a 3d-XY quantum phase transition to the polarized high-field
phase. For $J_3&gt;J_2$, an order-by-disorder mechanism stabilizes a distinct
$k=(0,0)$ order and a quantum phase transition in the 3d-Ising universality
class is observed. In contrast to the triangular lattice, on the ruby lattice
algebraically decaying long-range interactions favor the clock-ordered
low-field phase and therefore allow a robust implementation in existing Rydberg
atom quantum simulators.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>A. Duft</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>J. A. Koziol</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>P. Adelhardt</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>M. Mühlhauser</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>K. P. Schmidt</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">22 pages, 16 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12941v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2312.12941v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.str-el" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.quant-gas" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
